Let's get started. So welcome to the very final lecture of the class.
让我们开始吧。欢迎来到课堂的最后一堂课。
I hope you're all surviving the last week and,
我希望你们在上周幸存下来，
uh, wrapping up your projects.
呃，结束你的项目。
So today we're going to be hearing about the future of NLP and deep learning.
所以今天我们将会听到NLP和深度学习的未来。
Uh, so Chris is still traveling and today we're going to be having Kevin Clark,
呃，所以克里斯还在旅行，今天我们将要有凯文克拉克，
who's one of the PhD students in the lab, uh,
谁是实验室的博士生之一，呃，
in the NLP lab,
在NLP实验室，
and he was also one of the head TAs for the class last year.
去年他也是该班的首席助教之一。
So he's very familiar with the class as a whole.
所以他对整个班级非常熟悉。
Um, so, take it away Kevin.
嗯，把它带走凯文。
Okay. Thanks, Abby. Um, yeah,
好的。谢谢，艾比。嗯，是的，
it's great to be back after being a TA last year.
去年成为TA后回来真好。
Um, I'm really excited today to be talking about the future of deep learning and NLP.
嗯，今天我真的很兴奋谈论深度学习和NLP的未来。
Um, obviously, trying to forecast the future, um,
嗯，显然，试图预测未来，嗯，
for deep learning or anything in that space is really
深度学习或那个空间中的任何东西都是真的
difficult because the field is changing super quickly.
困难，因为该领域正在快速变化。
Um, so as one reference point, um,
嗯，作为一个参考点，嗯，
let's look at what did deep learning for NLP,
让我们来看看NLP的深度学习，
um, look like about five years ago.
嗯，看起来大约五年前。
And really, a lot of ideas that are now considered to be pretty core techniques,
实际上，很多想法现在被认为是非常核心的技术，
um, when we think of deep learning and NLP,
嗯，当我们想到深度学习和NLP时，
um, didn't even exist back then.
嗯，那时候甚至不存在。
Um, so things you learned in this class like Seq2Seq,
嗯，你在这堂课上学到的东西就像Seq2Seq，
attention mechanism, um, large-scale,
注意机制，嗯，大规模，
reading comprehension, uh, even frameworks
阅读理解，呃，甚至是框架
such as TensorFlow or Pytorch, um, didn't exist.
比如TensorFlow或Pytorch，嗯，不存在。
And, uh, the point I want to make with this is that, um,
而且，呃，我想用这个做点是，嗯，
because of this it's really difficult to, to look into the future and say,
因为这样，展望未来真的很难说，
okay, what are things going to be like?
好吧，会发生什么事情？
Um, what I think we can do though is look at, um,
嗯，我认为我们可以做的就是看，嗯，
areas that right now are really sort of taking off, um,
现在的地方真的有点起飞，嗯，
so areas in which, um,
那些领域，嗯，
there's a lot, been a lot of recent success and kind of, uh,
有很多，最近有很多成功，有点，呃，
project from that, that,
那个项目，那个，
those same areas will likely be important in the future.
这些相同的领域将来可能很重要。
Um, and in this talk I'm going to be mostly focusing on one key idea of
嗯，在这次演讲中，我将主要关注一个关键的想法
wh- key idea which is the idea of leveraging
什么是关键的想法，这是利用的想法
unlabeled examples when training our NLP systems.
训练我们的NLP系统时没有标记的例子。
So I'll be talking a bit about doing that for machine translation, um,
所以我会谈谈为机器翻译做这件事，嗯，
both in improving the quality of translation and even
两者都在提高翻译质量甚至
in doing a translation in an unsupervised way.
以无人监督的方式进行翻译。
So that means you don't have, um,
这意味着你没有，嗯，
paired sentences, uh, with, with their translations.
成对的句子，呃，用，和他们的翻译。
Um, you try to learn a translation model only from a monolingual corpus.
嗯，你试图只从单语语料库中学习翻译模型。
Um, the second thing I'll be talking a little bit about is, uh,
嗯，我要谈的第二件事是，呃，
OpenAI's GPT-2, um,
OpenAI的GPT-2，嗯，
and in general this phenomenon of really scaling up,
而且一般来说这种现象非常大，
um, deep learning models.
嗯，深度学习模型。
Um, I know you saw a little bit of this in the lecture on contextual representations,
嗯，我知道你在关于语境表征的讲座中看到了一点点，
but this, but this will be a little bit more in depth.
但是这个，但这会更深入一点。
Um, and I think, um,
嗯，我想，嗯，
these new developments in NLP have had some,
NLP的这些新发展有一些，
um, pretty big, uh,
嗯，很大，呃，
impacts in terms of,
影响，
uh, more broadly kind of beyond even the technology we're using,
呃，更广泛地说，甚至超越了我们正在使用的技术，
and in particular, I mean,
特别是，我的意思是，
starting to raise more and more concerns about the social impact of NLP, um,
开始对NLP的社会影响提出越来越多的担忧，嗯，
both, um, in what our models can do and also in kind
嗯，我们的模型可以做什么，也可以做
of plans of what, where people are looking to apply these models, um,
人们希望应用这些模型的计划，嗯，
and I think that really has some risks associated with it, um,
而且我认为这确实存在一些与之相关的风险，嗯，
in terms of security also in terms of areas like bias.
在安全方面也是偏见等方面。
Um, I'm also gonna talk a bit about future areas of research,
嗯，我还要谈谈未来的研究领域，
um, these are mostly research areas now that are, um,
嗯，现在这些都是研究领域，嗯，
over the past year have really kind of developed into
在过去的一年里真的有点发展成了
promising areas and I expect they will continue to be important in the future.
有希望的领域，我希望它们在未来继续发挥重要作用。
Okay, um, to start with,
好的，嗯，首先，
I wanna ask this question, why has deep learning been so successful recently?
我想问这个问题，为什么最近深度学习如此成功？
Um, I like this comic, um,
嗯，我喜欢这个漫画，嗯，
here there's a statistical learning person,
这里有一个统计学习者，
um, and they've got some really complicated,
嗯，他们有一些非常复杂的，
um, well-motivated, uh, method for doing, um,
嗯，精力充沛，呃，做的方法，嗯，
the task they care about,
他们关心的任务，
and then the neural net person just says,
然后神经网络的人说，
er, stack more layers.
呃，堆叠更多层。
Um, so, so the point I want to make here is that, um,
嗯，所以我想在这里说的是，嗯，
deep learning has not been successful recently because it's more
深度学习最近并没有成功，因为它更多
theoretically motivated or it's more sophisticated than previous techniques, um.
嗯，理论上有动力或比以前的技术更复杂。
In fact I would say that actually a lot of, um,
事实上，我会说实际上很多，嗯，
older statistical methods have more of
较旧的统计方法有更多
a theoretical underpinning than some of the tricks we do in deep learning.
理论基础而不是我们在深度学习中所做的一些技巧。
Um, really the thing that makes deep learning so
嗯，真的是深入学习的东西
successful in recent years has been its ability to scale, right.
近年来成功的是它的扩展能力，对吧。
So neural nets, as we increase the size of the data,
所以神经网络，随着我们增加数据的大小，
as we increase the size of the models, um,
当我们增加模型的大小时，嗯，
they get a really big boost in accuracy,
他们的准确性得到了极大的提升，
in ways other approaches do not.
其他方法没有。
And, um, if you look to the '80s and '90s, um,
而且，嗯，如果你看看80年代和90年代，嗯，
there was actually plenty of research in neural nets going on, um.
实际上有很多关于神经网络的研究，嗯。
But it hadn't, doesn't have a hype around it that it does
但它没有，它没有围绕它做炒作
now and that seems likely to be because,
现在，这似乎可能是因为，
um, in the past there wasn't, um,
嗯，过去没有，嗯，
the same resources in terms of computers,
计算机方面的资源相同，
in terms of data and, um,
就数据而言，嗯，
only now after we've reached sort of an inflection point where we can
直到我们达到了一个拐点，我们才能做到
really take advantage of scale in
真正利用规模
our deep learning models and we started to see it become,
我们的深度学习模式，我们开始看到它，
um, a really successful paradigm for machine learning.
嗯，这是一个非常成功的机器学习范例。
Um, if we look at big, uh,
嗯，如果我们看一下大，呃，
deep learning success stories, um,
深度学习成功的故事，嗯，
I think, uh, you can see kind of this idea play out, right?
我想，呃，你可以看到这种想法发挥出来，对吧？
So here are three of what are arguably the most famous successes of deep learning, right.
所以这里有三个可以说是深度学习中最着名的成功，对吧。
So there's image recognition, where before,
所以有图像识别，以前，
people used very highly engineered, um,
人们使用非常高度工程，嗯，
features to classify images and now neural nets are much superior, um, to those methods.
对图像进行分类的功能现在神经网络对这些方法来说是非常优越的。
Um, machine translation has really closed the gap between, um,
嗯，机器翻译真的缩小了，嗯，
phrase-based systems and human quality translation,
基于短语的系统和人类素质翻译，
so this is widely used in things like Google Translate
所以这被广泛用于谷歌翻译
and the quality has actually gotten a lot better over the past five years.
在过去的五年里，质量实际上已经变得更好了。
Um, another example that had a lot of hype around it is game-playing, so, um,
嗯，另一个有很多炒作的例子是游戏，所以，嗯，
there's been work on Atari games, there's been AlphaGo,
有关Atari游戏的工作，有AlphaGo，
uh, more recently there's been AlphaStar and OpenAI Five.
呃，最近有AlphaStar和OpenAI Five。
Um, if you look at all three of these cases underlying
嗯，如果你看看所有这三个案例的基础
these successes is really large amounts of data, right.
这些成功实际上是大量的数据。
So for ImageNet, um,
对于ImageNet，嗯，
for image recognition, um,
用于图像识别，嗯，
there is the ImageNet dataset which has 14 million images,
ImageNet数据集有1400万张图像，
uh, machine translation datasets often have millions of examples.
呃，机器翻译数据集通常有数百万个例子。
Um, for game playing you can actually
嗯，对于玩游戏你实际上可以
generate as much training data as you want essentially,
尽可能多地生成训练数据，
um, just by running your agent,
嗯，只需运行你的代理，
um, within the game,
嗯，在游戏中，
um, over and over again.
嗯，一遍又一遍。
Um, so if we,
嗯，如果我们，
if we look to NLP, um,
如果我们看看NLP，嗯，
the story is quite a bit different for a lot of tasks, um, right.
对于很多任务来说，这个故事有点不同，嗯，对。
So if you look at even pretty core kind of popular tasks,
所以，如果你看一下非常核心的流行任务，
to say, reading comprehension in English, um,
用英语阅读理解，嗯，
datasets like SQuAD are in the order of like 100,000 examples
像SQUAD这样的数据集大约有100,000个例子
which is considerably less than the millions or tens of millions of examples,
这比数百万或数千万的例子少得多，
um, that these previous,
嗯，这些以前，
um, successes have, have benefited from.
嗯，成功了，从中受益了。
Um, and that's of course only for English, right.
嗯，这当然只适用于英语，对吧。
Um, there are, um,
嗯，有，嗯，
thousands of other languages and this is I think
成千上万的其他语言，我想
a problem with NLP data as it exists today.
如今存在的NLP数据存在问题。
Um, the vast majority of data is in English, um,
嗯，绝大多数数据是英文的，嗯，
when in reality fewer than 10% of the world's population,
实际上，这个世界人口不到10％，
um, speak English as their first language.
嗯，说英语作为他们的第一语言。
Um, so these problems with small datasets are only compounded if you look at,
嗯，所以如果你看一下，这些小数据集的问题只会复杂化，
um, the full spectrum of languages, um, that exist.
嗯，存在的各种语言，嗯。
Um, so, as what do we do,
嗯，所以，我们做什么，
uh, when we're limited by this data,
呃，当我们受到这些数据的限制时，
but we want to take advantage of deep learning scale and train the biggest models we can.
但是我们希望利用深度学习规模并培养我们能够做到的最大模型。
Um, the popular solution, um,
嗯，流行的解决方案，嗯，
that's especially had recent success is using unlabeled data, um,
最近成功的是使用未标记的数据，嗯，
because unlike labeled data,
因为与标记数据不同，
unlabeled data is very easy to acquire for language.
未标记的数据很容易获得语言。
Um, you can just go to the Internet,
嗯，你可以去互联网，
you can go to books, you can get lots of text, um,
你可以去看书，你可以得到很多文字，嗯，
whereas labeled data usually requires at the least crowdsourcing examples.
而标签数据通常至少需要众包示例。
Um, in some cases you even require someone who's an expert in something like linguistics,
嗯，在某些情况下，你甚至需要一个像语言学这样的专家，
um, to, to annotate that data.
嗯，要注释那些数据。
Okay, so, um, this first part of the talk is going to be applying
好吧，嗯，这个演讲的第一部分将会应用
this idea of leveraging unlabeled data to improve our NLP models,
利用未标记数据来改进我们的NLP模型的想法，
um, to the task of machine translation.
嗯，对机器翻译的任务。
Um, so let's talk about machine translation data.
嗯，让我们来谈谈机器翻译数据。
Um, it is true that there do exist quite large datasets for machine translation.
嗯，确实存在用于机器翻译的相当大的数据集。
Um, those datasets don't exist because
嗯，那些数据集不存在，因为
NLP researchers have annotated texts for the purpose of training their models, right.
对于训练他们的模型，NLP研究人员已经注释了文本，对吧。
They exist because, er, in various settings,
它们的存在是因为，呃，在各种环境中，
translation is done just because it's useful, so for example,
翻译只是因为它很有用，所以例如，
proceedings of the European Parliament,
欧洲议会的议事程序，
um, proceedings of the United Nations,
嗯，联合国会议记录，
um, some, uh, news sites, they translate their articles into many languages.
嗯，有些，呃，新闻网站，他们把文章翻译成多种语言。
Um, so really, the machine translation data we use to train our models are often
嗯，实际上，我们用来训练模型的机器翻译数据经常是
more of byproducts of existing cases where translation is wanted rather than,
更多需要翻译的现有案例的副产品，而不是
um, kind of a full sampling of the sort of text we see in the world.
嗯，这是我们在世界上看到的那种文本的完整样本。
Um, so that means number one,
嗯，这意味着第一，
it's quite limited in domain, right.
它在域中非常有限，对吧。
So it's not easy to find translated tweets,
所以找到翻译的推文并不容易，
um, unless you happen to work for Twitter.
嗯，除非你碰巧在Twitter上工作。
Um, in addition to that, um,
嗯，除此之外，嗯，
there's limitations in terms of the languages that are covered, right.
对于涵盖的语言而言，这是有限制的。
So some languages, say European languages,
有些语言，比如欧洲语言，
there's a lot of translation data, um,
有很多翻译数据，嗯，
for other languages there's much less.
对于其他语言来说，要少得多。
Um, so in these settings where we want to work on
嗯，所以在我们想要处理的这些环境中
a different domain or where we want to work with a low resource language,
一个不同的域或我们想要使用低资源语言的地方，
um, we're limited by labeled data, um,
嗯，我们受到标签数据的限制，嗯，
but what we can do is pretty easily find unlabeled data.
但我们能做的就是很容易找到未标记的数据。
Um, so it's actually a pretty solved problem, um,
嗯，所以这实际上是一个非常解决的问题，嗯，
maybe not 100%, but we can with good accuracy look at
也许不是100％，但我们可以很好的准确看待
some text and decide what language it's in and train a classifier to do that.
一些文本并决定它所使用的语言并训练分类器来做到这一点。
Um, so this means it's really easy to find
嗯，这意味着它很容易找到
data in any language you care about because you can just go on
您关心的任何语言的数据，因为您可以继续
the web and essentially search for data in
网络，基本上搜索数据
that language and acquire a large corpus of monolingual data.
那种语言并获得了大量的单语数据。
Okay, um, I'm now going into the first approach,
好的，嗯，我现在要进入第一种方法，
um, I'm going to talk about on using
嗯，我要谈谈使用
unlabeled data to improve machine translation models.
未标记的数据，以改善机器翻译模型。
Um, this technique is called pre-training and it's
嗯，这种技术叫做预训练，就是这样
really reminiscent of ideas like, um, ELMo.
真的让人想起像嗯，ELMo这样的想法。
Um, the idea is to pre-train by doing language modeling.
嗯，这个想法是通过语言建模来预训练。
So if we have, um,
如果我们有，嗯，
two languages we're interested in translating,
我们有兴趣翻译的两种语言，
um, from one end to the other,
嗯，从一端到另一端，
we'll collect large datasets for both of those languages and then we can train,
我们将收集这两种语言的大型数据集，然后我们可以训练，
uh, two language models,
呃，两种语言模型，
one each on that data and then, um,
一个关于那个数据然后，嗯，
we can use those, uh,
我们可以用那些，呃，
pre-trained language models as initialization for a machine translation system.
预先训练的语言模型作为机器翻译系统的初始化。
Um, so the encoder will get initialized with
嗯，编码器将初始化
the weights of the language model trained on the source side language, um,
用源语言语言训练的语言模型的权重，嗯，
the decoder will get initialized with weights trained on the target size language, uh,
解码器将使用目标大小语言训练的权重进行初始化，呃，
and this will, um,
这会，嗯，
improve the performance of your model because during this pre-training, um,
提高模型的性能，因为在这次预训练期间，嗯，
we hope that our language models will be learning useful information such as, you know,
我们希望我们的语言模型能够学习有用的信息，例如，
the meaning of words or, um, uh,
单词的意思或者，嗯，呃，
the kind of structure of the language, um,
这种语言的结构，嗯，
they are processing, um, and this can, uh,
他们正在处理，嗯，这可以，呃，
down the line help the machine translation model,
下线帮助机器翻译模型，
um, when we fine tune it.
嗯，当我们微调它。
Um, let me pause here and ask if there are any questions,
嗯，让我暂停一下，询问是否有任何问题，
and just in general, feel,
一般来说，感觉，
feel free to ask questions throughout this talk. Okay.
在整个演讲中随时提出问题。好的。
So, so here is a plot showing some results of this pre-training technique.
所以，这里有一个图表显示了这种预训练技术的一些结果。
Um, so this is English to German translation.
嗯，这是英语到德语的翻译。
Uh, the x-axis is how much training data,
呃，x轴是多少训练数据，
as in unsupervised training data, um,
和无人监督的训练数据一样，嗯，
you provide these models,
你提供这些模型，
but of course they also have large amounts
但当然他们也有很多
of monolingual data for this pre-training step.
这个预训练步骤的单语数据。
And you can see that this works pretty well, right?
你可以看到这很好用，对吗？
So you've got about two blue points, um,
所以你有两个蓝点，嗯，
increase in performance, so that's this red line above the blue line,
性能提高，所以这条红线高于蓝线，
um, when doing this pre-training technique.
嗯，在做这种预训练技术时。
And not too surprisingly,
并不奇怪，
this gain is especially large when the amount of labeled data is small.
当标记数据量很小时，这种增益特别大。
Um, there is a problem with,
嗯，有问题，
uh, pre-training which I want to address, which is that, uh,
呃，我想要解决的预训练，就是那个，呃，
in pre-training, you have
在预训练中，你有
these two separate language models and there's never
这两个独立的语言模型，从来没有
really any interaction between the two,
真的是两者之间的任何互动，
um, when you're running them on the unlabeled corpus.
嗯，当你在未标记的语料库上运行它们时。
Um, so here's a simple technique, um,
嗯，所以这是一个简单的技术，嗯，
that tries to solve this problem and it's called self-training.
试图解决这个问题，它被称为自我训练。
Um, the idea is given a sentence from our monolingual corpus,
嗯，这个想法是从我们的单语语料库中给出一个句子，
so in this case, "I traveled to Belgium," that's an English sentence.
所以在这种情况下，“我前往比利时”，这是一个英文句子。
Um, we won't have a human provided translation for this sentence, uh,
嗯，我们不会为这句话提供人为翻译，呃，
but what we can do is we can run our machine translation model,
但我们能做的就是运行我们的机器翻译模型，
and we'll get a translation in the target language.
我们将获得目标语言的翻译。
Um, since this is from a machine learning model it won't be perfect, uh,
嗯，因为这是一个机器学习模型，它不会是完美的，呃，
but we can hope that maybe our model can still learn from this kind
但我们希望我们的模型仍然可以从这种模式中学习
of noisy labeled example, right?
嘈杂的标签示例，对吧？
So we, we treat, um,
所以，我们，我们对待，嗯，
our original monolingual sentence and it's machine-provided
我们原来的单语句子和机器提供的
translation as though it were a human-provided translation and,
翻译好像是人为翻译的，
uh, train our machine learning model as normal on this example.
呃，在这个例子中正常训练我们的机器学习模型。
Um, I think this seems pretty strange actually as- as
嗯，我觉得这实际上看起来很奇怪
a method when you first see it because it seems really circular, right?
当你第一次看到它时，因为它看起来真的是圆形的，对吗？
So if you look at this, um, the, uh,
所以，如果你看看这个，嗯，呃，
translation that the model is being trained to
正在训练模型的翻译
produce is actually exactly what it already produces to begin with,
产品实际上就是它开始生产的产品，
right, because, um, this translation came from our model in the first place.
是的，因为，嗯，这个翻译首先来自我们的模型。
Um, so actually in practice,
嗯，实际上在实践中，
this is not a technique that's very widely used due to this problem,
由于这个问题，这不是一种被广泛使用的技术，
um, but it motivates another technique called back-translation.
嗯，但它激发了另一种称为反向翻译的技术。
And this technique is really a very popular, um,
这种技术真的非常流行，嗯，
solution to that problem, and it's the method, um,
这个问题的解决方案，这是方法，嗯，
that has had a lot of success in using unlabeled data for translation.
在使用未标记的数据进行翻译方面取得了很大成功。
So here's the approach rather than only
所以这是方法，而不仅仅是
having our translation system that goes from source language to target language,
我们的翻译系统从源语言到目标语言，
um, we're also going to train a model that
嗯，我们也要训练一个模型
goes from our target language to our source language.
从我们的目标语言到我们的源语言。
And so in this case, if,
在这种情况下，如果，
if at the end of the day we want a French to English model, um,
如果在一天结束时我们想要一个法语到英语的模型，嗯，
we're gonna start by actually training an English to French model.
我们将从实际培训英语到法语模型开始。
And then we can do something that's a lot like self-labeling.
然后我们可以做一些像自我标记的事情。
So we take a English sentence.
所以我们用英语句子。
We run our English to French model and translate it.
我们运行英语到法语模型并进行翻译。
The difference to what we did before is that
与我们之前所做的不同之处在于
we're actually going to switch the source and target side.
我们实际上要切换源和目标端。
So now in this case the French sentence is the source sequence.
所以现在在这种情况下，法语句子是源序列。
Uh, the target sequence is, um,
呃，目标序列是，嗯，
our original English sentence that came from  monolingual corpora.
我们原来的英语句子来自单语语料库。
And now we're training the language, uh,
现在我们正在训练语言，呃，
the machine translation system that goes
去机器翻译系统
the other direction so that goes French to English.
另一个方向是法语到英语。
Um, so, so why do we think this will work better?
嗯，那么，为什么我们认为这会更好？
Um, number one, um,
嗯，头号，嗯，
there's no longer this kind of circularity to the training
这种训练不再具有这种循环性
because what the model is being trained on is the output of a completely different model.
因为正在训练的模型是完全不同模型的输出。
Um, another thing that I think is pretty crucial here is that,
嗯，我认为另一件非常关键的事情是，
um, the translations, the model is trained to produce.
嗯，翻译，模型训练生产。
So the things that the decoder is actually learning to
所以解码器实际上正在学习的东西
generate are never bad translations, right?
生成从来都不是坏翻译，对吗？
So if you look at this example,
所以，如果你看看这个例子，
the target sequence for our French to English model,
我们的法语到英语模型的目标序列，
I traveled to Belgium, um,
我去了比利时，嗯，
that originally came from a monolingual corpus.
最初来自单语语料库。
Um, so I think intuitively this makes sense is
嗯，所以我觉得这很有意义
that if we want to train a good translation model,
如果我们想培养一个好的翻译模型，
um, it's probably okay to expose it to noisy inputs.
嗯，把它暴露在嘈杂的输入中可能是可以的。
So we expose it to the output of a system that's English to French,
所以我们把它暴露给一个英语到法语系统的输出，
it might not be perfect.
它可能不完美。
Um, but what we don't want to do is um, expose it to
嗯，但我们不想做的是嗯，把它暴露给
poor target sequences because then it
糟糕的目标序列，因为它
won't learn how to generate in that language effectively.
不会学习如何有效地用这种语言生成。
Any questions on back-translation before I get to results? Um, sure.
在我得到结果之前有关于反向翻译的任何问题吗？嗯，当然。
[BACKGROUND]
[背景]
So this is assuming we have a large corpus of
所以这假设我们有一个大的语料库
unlabeled data and we want to be using it to help our translation model.
未标记的数据，我们希望用它来帮助我们的翻译模型。
Does that, does that make sense?
那是否有意义？
Um, maybe you could clarify the question.
嗯，也许你可以澄清这个问题。
[BACKGROUND]
[背景]
Yeah, that's right. So we have a big corpus of English which includes the sentence,
是啊，没错。所以我们有一个很大的英语语料库，包括句子，
"I traveled to Belgium," and we don't know the translations but we'd still like to
“我前往比利时，”我们不知道翻译，但我们仍然喜欢
use this data. Yeah, another question.
使用这些数据。是的，另一个问题。
[BACKGROUND]
[背景]
Yeah, so that's a good question is how do you
是的，这是一个很好的问题，你是怎么做的
avoid both the models let's say sort of blowing up and producing garbage?
避免两种模型让我们说有点炸毁和生产垃圾？
And then they're just feeding garbage to each other.
然后他们只是互相喂垃圾。
The answer is that there is some amount of labeled data here as well.
答案是这里也有一些标记数据。
So on unlabeled data you do this, but on labeled data,
因此，对于未标记的数据，您可以执行此操作，但对于标记数据，
you do standard training,
你做标准培训，
and that way you avoid, you,
这样你就可以避免，
you make sure you kind of keep the models on track because they still have to fit to
你确保你保持模型正常，因为他们仍然必须适应
the labeled data. Yeah, another question.
标签数据。是的，另一个问题。
How do you schedule the training of the two models?
你如何安排两种模型的培训？
Yeah, that is a good question.
是的，这是一个很好的问题。
And I think that's basically almost like a hyper-parameter you can tweak.
而且我认为这基本上就像一个你可以调整的超参数。
So I think a pretty common thing to do is first,
所以我认为一件非常普遍的事情是，
train two models only on labeled data.
仅在标记数据上训练两个模型。
Then label, um, so then do back-translation
然后标签，嗯，然后进行反向翻译
over a large corpus and kind of repeat that process over and over again.
在一个大的语料库上，一遍又一遍地重复这个过程。
So each iteration, you train on the label data,
所以每次迭代，你都要对标签数据进行训练，
label some unlabeled data and now you have more data to work with.
标记一些未标记的数据，现在您可以使用更多数据。
But I think there'd be many kinds of scheduling that would be effective
但我认为有很多类型的调度是有效的
here. Okay. Another question.
这里。好的。另一个问题。
I'm curious as to the evaluation, considering if you have a very good French to English model, you could try to look up, or contest if you have a good French to English model, you could try to look up the original source and see if it matches.
我很好奇评价，考虑到你是否有一个非常好的法语到英语模型，你可以尝试查找，或者如果你有一个很好的法语到英语模型的比赛，你可以尝试查找原始来源和看它是否匹配。
Yeah, I'm not, I'm not quite sure.
是的，我不是，我不太确定。
Are you suggesting going like English to French to English and seeing if?
你是建议像英语到法语到英语，看看是否？
I see, yeah, yeah,
我明白了，是的，是的，
that's a really interesting idea.
这是一个非常有趣的想法。
And we're actually going to talk a little bit about this sort of,
我们实际上会谈谈这种，
it's called cycle consistency,
它被称为循环一致性，
this idea later in this talk.
这个想法后来在这个演讲中。
Okay, I'm going to move on to the results.
好的，我将继续讨论结果。
So, so here's the method for using unlabeled data to improve translation.
所以，这里是使用未标记数据来改进翻译的方法。
How well does it do?
它有多好？
Um, the answer is that the improvements are at least to me, they
嗯，答案是这些改进至少对我而言，他们
were surprisingly extremely good, right?
出奇的非常好，对吧？
So, um, this is for English to German translation.
所以，嗯，这是英语到德语的翻译。
This is from some work by Facebook, so they  used 5 million labeled sentence pairs.
这是来自Facebook的一些工作，因此他们使用了500万个带标签的句子对。
But they also used 230 monolingual sentences, so sentences without translations.
但他们也使用了230个单语句子，所以句子没有翻译。
And you can see that compared to previous state of the art,
你可以看到，与以前的技术水平相比，
they get six BLEU points improvement which, um,
他们获得了六个BLEU积分改善，嗯，
if you compare it to most previous research and machine tran- machine translation
如果你把它与大多数以前的研究和机器翻译机进行比较
is a really big gain, right?
是一个非常大的收获，对吗？
So even something like the invention of the transformer which most people would
所以即使是大多数人都会想到的变压器的发明
consider to be a really significant research development in NLP,
考虑成为NLP真正重要的研究发展，
that improved over prior work by about 2,5 BLEU points.
比先前的工作提高了约2,5 BLEU积分。
And here without doing any sort of fancy model design just by using way more data,
这里没有采用任何类型的花式模型设计，只需使用更多的数据，
um, we get actually much larger improvements.
嗯，我们实际上得到了更大的改进。
Okay. So an interesting question to think about,
好的。这是一个值得思考的有趣问题，
um, is suppose we only have our monolingual corpora.
嗯，假设我们只有单语语料库。
So we don't have any sentences that had been human translated.
所以我们没有任何人为翻译过的句子。
We just have sentences in two languages.
我们只有两种语言的句子。
Um, so the scenario you can sort of imagine is suppose,
嗯，你可以想象的场景是假设的，
um, an alien comes down and,
嗯，一个外星人来了，
um, starts talking to you and it's a
嗯，开始跟你说话，这是一个
weird alien language, um, and it talks a lot,
奇怪的外星语言，嗯，它谈了很多，
would you eventually be able to translate what it's saying to English,
你最终能够将它所说的翻译成英文，
um, just by having a really large amount of data?
嗯，只是拥有非常大量的数据？
Um, so I'm going to start with, um,
嗯，所以我要开始，嗯，
a simpler task than full-on translating when you only have unlabeled sentences.
当你只有未标记的句子时，比完全翻译更简单的任务。
Um, instead of doing sentence to sentence translation,
嗯，而不是做句子翻译，
let's start by only worrying about word to word translation.
让我们首先担心单词翻译。
So the goal here is given a word in one language,
所以这里的目标用一种语言表达，
find its translation but without using any labeled data.
找到它的翻译但不使用任何标记数据。
Um, and the method,
嗯，方法，
the method we're going to use to try to solve
我们将尝试解决的方法
this task is called, uh, cross-lingual embeddings.
这个任务被称为，呃，跨语言嵌入。
Um, so the goal is to learn, uh,
嗯，所以我的目标是学习，呃，
word vectors for words in both languages,
两种语言中单词的单词向量，
and we'd like those word vectors to have
我们希望这些单词向量具有
all the nice properties you've already learned about word vectors having, um,
你已经学过的有关单词向量的所有好的属性，嗯，
but we also want word vectors for a particular language,
但我们也想要特定语言的单词向量，
um, to be close to the word vector of its translation.
嗯，接近它翻译的单词vector。
Um, so I'm not sure if it's visible in this figure but this fis- figure shows
嗯，所以我不确定它是否在这个图中可见，但这个fis-数字显示
a large number of English and I think German words and you can see that,
大量的英语和我认为德语单词，你可以看到，
um, uh, the each English word has its corresponding German word,
嗯，呃，每个英文单词都有相应的德语单词，
um, nearby to it in its embedding space.
嗯，在它的嵌入空间附近。
So if we learn embeddings like this then it's pretty easy to do word to word translation.
因此，如果我们学习这样的嵌入，那么单词翻译就很容易了。
Um, we just pick an English word,
嗯，我们只选一个英文单词，
we find the nearest, uh,
我们找到最近的，呃，
German word in this joint embedding space
这个联合嵌入空间中的德语单词
and that will give us a translation for the English word.
这将为我们提供英文单词的翻译。
Um, our key method for or the key
嗯，我们的关键方法或关键
assumption that we're going to be using to solve this is that,
假设我们将要用来解决这个问题，
um, th- even though if you run word2vec twice you'll get really different embeddings.
嗯，即使你运行word2vec两次，你会得到真正不同的嵌入。
Um, the structure of that embedding space has a lot of regularity to it,
嗯，嵌入空间的结构有很多规律性，
and we can take advantage of that regularity, um,
我们可以利用这种规律性，嗯，
to help find when,
帮助找到什么时候，
um, an alignment between those embedding spaces.
嗯，那些嵌入空间之间的对齐。
So to be kind of more concrete here.
所以在这里要更具体一点。
Here is a picture of two sets of word embeddings.
这是两组字嵌入的图片。
So in red, we have, um,
所以红色，我们有，嗯，
English words, in, uh,
英文单词，in，呃，
blue we have Italian words,
蓝色我们有意大利语单词，
and although, um, the vector spaces right now look very different to each other,
虽然，嗯，现在的矢量空间看起来彼此非常不同，
um, you can see that they have a really similar structure, right?
嗯，你可以看到它们的结构非常相似，对吧？
So you'd imagine distances are kind of similar that the distance from,
所以你可以想象距离有点类似于距离，
uh, cat and feline in the, um,
呃，猫和猫在，嗯，
English embedding space should be pretty similar to the distance
英语嵌入空间应该与距离非常相似
between gatto and felino in the, um, Italian space.
意大利空间中的gatto和felino之间。
Um, this kind of motivates an algorithm for learning these cross-lingual embeddings.
嗯，这种激发了学习这些跨语言嵌入的算法。
Um, so here's the idea.
嗯，所以这就是主意。
What we're going to try to do is learn what's essentially
我们要做的是从本质上学习什么
a rotation such that we can transform,
我们可以改变的旋转，
um, our set of English embeddings so
嗯，我们的英语嵌入集合如此
that they match up with our Italian embe- embeddings.
它们与我们的意大利嵌入式相匹配。
So mathematically, what this means is we're gonna learn
所以在数学上，这意味着我们要学习
a matrix W such that if we take let's say,
矩阵W，如果我们采取让我们说，
uh, the word vector for cat in English and we multiply it by W, um,
呃，用英语写的“猫”一词，我们将它乘以W，嗯，
we end up with the vector for gatto in Spanish or Italian,
我们最终得到西班牙语或意大利语的gatto矢量，
um, and a detail here is that, um,
嗯，这里的细节是，嗯，
we're going to constrain W to be orthogonal, um,
我们要约束W是正交的，嗯，
and what that means geometrically is just that W is
几何上的意思就是W就是
only going to be doing a rotation to the,
只会做一个轮换，
uh, vectors, um, in X.
呃，矢量，嗯，在X.
It's not going to be doing some other weirder transformation.
它不会做其他一些奇怪的改造。
So this is our goal is to learn this W. Um,
所以这是我们的目标是学习这个W.嗯，
next I'm gonna talk about,
接下来我要谈谈，
talking about how actually do we learn this W. Um,
谈论我们实际上是如何学习这个W.嗯，
and there's actually a bunch of techniques for learning this W matrix,
实际上有一堆学习这个W矩阵的技术，
um, but, um, here is one of
嗯，但是，嗯，这是其中之一
them that I think is quite clever is called adversarial training.
我认为非常聪明的人称为对抗训练。
Um, so it works as follows,
嗯，所以它的工作原理如下，
is in addition to trying to learn this W matrix,
除了试图学习这个W矩阵，
we're also going to be trying to learn a model that, uh,
我们也将试图学习一个模型，呃，
is called a discriminator,
被称为鉴别器，
and what it'll do is take a vector and it will try to predict,
它会做什么是采取矢量，它会尝试预测，
is that vector originally, um,
是那个矢量最初，嗯，
an English word embedding or is it originally an Italian word embedding?
英语单词嵌入还是原来是意大利语单词嵌入？
Um, in other words, if you think about, um,
嗯，换句话说，如果你想的话，嗯，
the diagram, what we're asking our discriminator to do is, uh,
图，我们要求我们的鉴别者做的是，呃，
it's given one of these points and it's trying to predict is it
它给出了其中一个点，并试图预测它是什么
basically a red point so an English word originally, or is it a blue point?
基本上是红点，所以最初是英文单词，还是蓝点？
Um, so if we have no W matrix and this is
嗯，所以如果我们没有W矩阵，那就是
a really easy task for the discriminator because,
鉴别器真的很容易，因为，
um, the, uh, word embeddings for English and Italian are clearly separated.
嗯，呃，英语和意大利语的嵌入词是明显分开的。
Um, however, if we learn a W matrix
嗯，如果我们学习W矩阵
that succeeds in aligning all these embeddings on top of each other,
成功地将所有这些嵌入对齐，
then our discriminator will never do a good job, right.
那么我们的鉴别者永远不会做得好，对吧。
We can imagine it'll never really do better than 50%,
我们可以想象它永远不会超过50％，
um, because given a vector for say cat,
嗯，因为给了一个说猫的矢量，
it won't know is that the vector for cat that's been
它不会知道是猫的矢量
transformed by W or is it actually the vector for gatto?
由W转换或它实际上是gatto的向量？
Um, because in this case those two vectors are aligned so they are on top of each other.
嗯，因为在这种情况下，这两个向量是对齐的，所以它们在彼此的顶部。
Um, so, um, during training, you first, um,
嗯，所以，嗯，在训练期间，你首先，嗯，
you alternate between training the discriminator a little bit which
你之间交替训练鉴别器一点点
means making sure it's as good as possible at
意味着确保它尽可能好
distinguishing the English from Italian words and then you
区分英语和意大利语然后你
train the W and the goal for training W is to,
训练W和训练W的目标是，
uh, essentially confuse the discriminator as much as possible.
呃，基本上尽可能地混淆鉴别者。
Um, so you want to have a situation where,
嗯，所以你想要有一种情况，
um, you can't, um, with this machine learning model,
嗯，你不能，嗯，这个机器学习模型，
figure out if a word embedding actually, um,
弄清楚实际嵌入一个单词，嗯，
was, um, originally from English or if it's an Italian word vector.
是，嗯，最初来自英语，或者它是一个意大利语单词矢量。
Um, and so at the end of the day you have,
嗯，等你结束的那天，
you have vectors that are kind of aligned with each other.
你有一些彼此对齐的向量。
Um, any questions about this approach?
嗯，有关这种方法的任何问题吗？
Okay. Um, he- there's a link to a paper with more details.
好的。嗯，他 - 这是一篇关于更多细节的论文的链接。
There's actually kind of a range of other tricks you can do,
实际上你可以做一些其他的技巧，
um, but this is kind of a key idea.
嗯，但这是一个关键的想法。
Um, okay. So that was doing word to word unsupervised translation.
嗯，好的。所以这就是无人监督的翻译。
Um, how do we do full sentence to sentence translation?
嗯，我们怎么做句子翻译？
Um, so we're going to use, um,
嗯，我们打算用，嗯，
a standard sort of seq2seq model,
一种标准的seq2seq模型，
um, without even an attention mechanism.
嗯，甚至没有注意机制。
Um, there's one change to the standard seq2seq
嗯，标准seq2seq有一个变化
model going on here which is that, um,
模特继续在这就是那个，嗯，
we're going to use the same encoder and decoder,
我们将使用相同的编码器和解码器，
uh, regardless of the input and output languages.
呃，不管输入和输出语言。
So you can see, um,
所以你可以看到，嗯，
in this example, um,
在这个例子中，嗯，
we could give the encoder an English sentence,
我们可以给编码器一个英文句子，
we could also give it a French sentence and it'll have these cross-lingual embeddings.
我们也可以给它一个法语句子，它将有这些跨语言嵌入。
So it'll have vector representations for English words
所以它会有英文单词的矢量表示
and French words which means it can handle sort of any input.
和法语单词，这意味着它可以处理任何输入。
Um, for the decoder,
嗯，对于解码器，
we need to give it some information about what language is it supposed to generate in.
我们需要给它一些关于它应该生成什么语言的信息。
Is it going to generate in French or English?
是用法语还是英语生成？
Um, so the way that is done is by, uh,
嗯，所以做的方式是，呃，
feeding in a special token which here is Fr
喂养一个特殊的标记，这里是Fr.
in brack- brackets to represent French that tells the model,
在括号中代表告诉模型的法语，
okay, you should generate in French now.
好吧，你现在应该用法语生成。
Um, here in this figure it's only French,
嗯，这个图中只有法语，
but you could imagine also feeding this model, uh,
但你可以想象也喂这个模型，呃，
English in brackets, and then that'll tell it to, uh, generate English.
括号中的英文，然后告诉它，呃，生成英语。
And one thing that you can see is that you could use this sort of model to g enerate,
你能看到的一件事就是你可以使用这种模型来加强，
do go from English to French.
从英语到法语。
You could also use this model as an auto-encoder, right.
您也可以将此模型用作自动编码器。
So, uh, at the bottom, um,
所以，呃，在底部，嗯，
it's taking in a French sentence as input and it's just generating French as
它以法语句子作为输入，它只是生成法语
output which here means just reproducing the original input sequence.
这里的输出意味着只是再现原始输入序列。
Um, so just a small change to standard seq2seq.
嗯，所以只需对标准seq2seq进行一些小改动。
Here's how we're going to train the seq2seq model.
以下是我们将如何训练seq2seq模型。
Um, there's going to be two training objectives, um,
嗯，这将是两个培训目标，嗯，
and I'll explain sort of why they're, uh,
我会解释为什么他们是，呃，
present in this model in just a few slides.
仅在几张幻灯片中出现在此模型中。
For now let's just say what they are.
现在让我们说出它们是什么。
So the first one is, um,
所以第一个是，嗯，
called a de-noising autoencoder.
称为去噪自动编码器。
Um, what we're going to train our model to do in this case is take a, uh, sentence.
嗯，在这种情况下，我们要训练我们的模型做的是拿一个，呃，句子。
So, um, and here it's going to be
那么，嗯，这就是它
an English sentence but it could also be a French sentence.
英语句子，但也可以是法语句子。
Um, we're going to scramble up the words a little bit,
嗯，我们要把这些话拼凑起来，
and then we're going to ask the model to, uh,
然后我们要问模型，呃，
de-noise that sentence which in other words means
消除那句话，换言之，意思是
regenerating what the sentence actually was before it was scrambled.
在它被扰乱之前重新生成句子实际上是什么。
And, uh, maybe one idea of why this would be a useful training objective is that,
而且，呃，或许有一个想法，为什么这将是一个有用的培训目标是，
uh, since we have an encoder-decoder without atten- attention,
呃，因为我们有一个没有注意的编码器 - 解码器，
the encoder is converting the entirety of the source sentence into a single vector,
编码器将整个源句子转换为单个向量，
what an auto-encoder does is ensure that that vector contains all the information about
自动编码器的作用是确保该向量包含有关的所有信息
the sentence such that we are able to recover what the original sentence was,
这句话使我们能够恢复原来的句子，
um, from the vector produced by the encoder.
嗯，来自编码器产生的矢量。
Um, so that was objective 1.
嗯，这是客观的1。
Training objective 2 is now we're actually going to be trying to do a translation,
培训目标2现在我们实际上将尝试进行翻译，
um, but, um, as before,
嗯，但是，嗯，和以前一样，
we're going to be using this back-translation idea.
我们将使用这种反向翻译的想法。
So remember, we only have unlabeled sentences,
所以请记住，我们只有无标签的句子，
we don't have any human-provided translations,
我们没有任何人工提供的翻译，
um, but what we can still do is, given, a,
嗯，但我们仍然可以做的是，给定，a，
um, let's say an English sentence or let's say a French sentence,
嗯，让我们说英语句子或者说法语句子，
given a French sentence, we can translate it to English, um,
鉴于法语判决，我们可以将其翻译成英语，嗯，
using our model in its current state, uh,
在当前状态下使用我们的模型，呃，
and then we can ask that model to translate from English or translate that- yeah,
然后我们可以要求该模型从英语翻译或翻译 - 是的，
translate that English back into French.
将英语翻译成法语。
Um, so what you can imagine is in this setting, um,
嗯，所以你能想象的就是这个环境，嗯，
the input sequence is going to be somewhat messed
输入序列会有些混乱
up because it's the output of our imperfect machine learning model.
因为它是我们不完美的机器学习模型的输出。
So here the input sequence is just "I am student," um, a word has been dropped,
所以这里的输入序列只是“我是学生”，嗯，一个单词已被删除，
but, um, we're now gonna train it to, even with this kind of bad input,
但是，嗯，我们现在要训练它，即使有这样糟糕的输入，
to reproduce the original, um,
重现原作，嗯，
French sentence, um, from our,
法语，嗯，来自我们，
uh, corpus of- of monolingual, um, French text.
呃，单语，嗯，法语文本的语料库。
[NOISE] Um, let me- let me pause here actually and ask for questions.
[NO]嗯，让我 - 让我暂停在这里，并提出问题。
Sure.
当然。
[NOISE] [inaudible] What if, um, the reason you have
[NOISE] [听不清]如果，嗯，你有什么原因
this orthogonality constraint for your words to be word embedding,
这个正交性约束你的单词嵌入，
is it to avoid overfitting?
是为了避免过度拟合？
Have you tried to take that off, and you know, see what [inaudible]
你有没有尝试过这个，你知道，看看[音频不清晰]
Yeah. That's a good question.
是啊。这是个好问题。
Um, so this is going back to earlier when there was a word-word translation.
嗯，所以这可以追溯到早些时候有一个单词翻译。
Why would we constrain that W matrix to be orthogonal?
为什么我们要将W矩阵约束为正交？
Um, essentially, that's right. It's to avoid overfitting and in particular,
嗯，基本上，这是对的。这是为了避免过度拟合，特别是
it's making this assumption that our embedding spaces are so
它假设我们的嵌入空间是这样的
similar that there's actually just a rotation that distinguishes,
类似的，实际上只是一个区分的轮换，
um, our word vectors in English versus our word vectors in Italian.
嗯，我们的单词矢量用英语对比我们的单词向量用意大利语。
Um, I think there has been, um,
嗯，我觉得有，嗯，
there have been results that don't include that orthogonality constraint,
有些结果不包括正交性约束，
and I think it slightly hurts performance to not have that in there.
而且我认为在那里没有那个有点伤害性能。
[NOISE] Okay.
[NOISE]好的。
Um, so- so continuing with,
嗯，马上继续，
um, unsupervised machine translation,
嗯，无人监督的机器翻译，
um, I- I gave a training method.
嗯，我 - 我给了一个训练方法。
I didn't quite explain why it would work, so- so,
我没有完全解释为什么它会起作用，所以，
um, here is some more intuition for- for this idea.
嗯，对于这个想法，这里有一些更直觉。
Um, so remember, um,
嗯，记得，嗯，
we're going to initialize
我们要初始化
our machine translation model with these cross-lingual embeddings,
我们的机器翻译模型与这些跨语言嵌入，
which mean the English and French word should look close to identically.
这意味着英语和法语单词看起来应该完全相同。
Um, we're also using the shared, um, encoder.
嗯，我们也在使用共享的嗯编码器。
Um, so that means if you think about it,
嗯，这意味着如果你考虑一下，
um, at the top, we have just,
嗯，在顶部，我们有，
a auto-encoding objective and we can certainly believe that our model can learn this.
一个自动编码的目标，我们当然可以相信我们的模型可以学到这一点。
Um, it's a pretty simple task.
嗯，这是一项非常简单的任务。
Um, now imagine we're giving our model a French sentence as input instead.
嗯，现在想象我们正在给我们的模型一个法语句子作为输入。
Um, since the, uh,
嗯，自从，呃，
embeddings are going to look pretty similar,
嵌入看起来非常相似，
and since the encoder is the same, um,
因为编码器是相同的，嗯，
it's pretty likely that the model's representation of
它很可能是该模型的代表
this French sentence should actually be very
这个法语句子应该是非常的
similar to the representation of the English sentence.
类似于英语句子的表示。
Um, so when this representation is passed into the decoder, um,
嗯，所以当这种表示传递给解码器时，嗯，
we can hope that we'll get the same output as before.
我们希望我们能够获得与以前相同的输出。
Um, um, so here's like sort of as a starting point.
嗯，嗯，所以这里就像一个起点。
We- we can hope that our model, um,
我们 - 我们可以希望我们的模型，嗯，
already is able to have some translation capability.
已经能够有一些翻译能力。
[NOISE] Um, another way of thinking about this is
[NOISE]嗯，另一种思考方式是
that what we really want our model to do is to be able to encode a sentence,
我们真正希望我们的模型做的是能够编码一个句子，
such that the representation,
这样的表示，
um, is sort of a universal kind of Interlingua.
嗯，是一种普遍的国际语。
So a universal, um, uh,
这是一个普遍的，嗯，呃，
universal representation of that sentence that doesn't,
这句话的普遍表示没有，
uh, that's not specific to the language.
呃，这不是语言特有的。
And so- so here's kind of a picture that's trying to get at this.
所以，这是一张试图解决这个问题的图片。
So our autoencoder, um, and our, um,
那么我们的autoencoder，嗯，我们的，嗯，
here in our back-translation example,
在我们的反向翻译示例中，
um, here, the target sequence is the same.
嗯，这里，目标序列是相同的。
[NOISE] Um, so what that essentially means is
[NOISE]嗯，所以这基本上意味着什么
that the vectors for the English sentence and the French sentence,
英语句子和法语句子的向量，
um, are going to be trained to be the same, um, right?
嗯，将会受到同样的训练，对吧？
Because if they are different, our, uh,
因为如果他们不同，我们，呃，
decoder would be generating different,
解码器会生成不同的，
uh, outputs on these two examples.
呃，这两个例子的输出。
Um, so here- this is just another sort of intuition is that what our model is
嗯，所以这里 - 这只是另一种直觉，就是我们的模型
trying to learn here is kind of a way of
试图在这里学习是一种方式
encoding the information of a sentence in a vector,
编码矢量中句子的信息，
um, but in a way that is language-agnostic.
嗯，但是这种方式与语言无关。
Um, any more questions about,
嗯，还有任何问题，
uh, unsupervised machine translation?
呃，无人监督的机器翻译？
Okay. Um, so going on to results of this approach, um,
好的。嗯，继续这种方法的结果，嗯，
here, the horizontal lines are,
这里，水平线是，
um, the results of an unsupervised machine translation model.
嗯，无监督机器翻译模型的结果。
Um, the lines that go up are for a supervised machine translation model,
嗯，上升的线是监督机器翻译模型，
um, as we give it more and more data.
嗯，因为我们给它提供了越来越多的数据。
Right? So unsurprisingly, um,
对？不出所料，嗯，
given a large amount of supervised data, um,
给出了大量的监督数据，嗯，
the supervised machine translation models
有监督的机器翻译模型
work much better than the unsupervised machine translation model.
比无人监督的机器翻译模型工作得更好。
Um, but, um, the unsupervised machine translation model,
嗯，但是，嗯，无人监督的机器翻译模型，
actually still does quite well.
实际上仍然做得很好。
Um, so if you see it around 10,000 to 100,000 training examples,
嗯，如果你看到大约10,000到100,000个训练样例，
um, it actually does just as well or better than supervised translation,
嗯，它实际上与监督翻译一样好或更好，
and I think that's a really promising result,
而且我认为这是一个非常有希望的结果，
uh, because if you think of, um,
呃，因为如果你想到的，嗯，
low-resource settings where there isn't much labeled examples, um,
资源不足的设置，没有太多标记的例子，嗯，
it suddenly becomes really nice that you can perform this well,
你突然变得非常好，你可以做得很好，
um, without even needing to use a training set.
嗯，甚至不需要使用训练集。
Um, another thing kind of fun you can do with,
嗯，你可以做的另一件好事，
an unsupervised machine translation model is attribute transfer.
无监督的机器翻译模型是属性转移。
Um, so basically, you can, um, take, uh,
嗯，基本上，你可以，嗯，接受，呃，
collections of texts that,
收集的文本，
uh, split by any attribute you want.
呃，按你想要的任何属性划分。
So for example, you could go on Twitter,
例如，你可以去推特，
look at hashtags to decide which tweets are annoyed and which tweets are relaxed,
查看主题标签以确定哪些推文令人生气，哪些推文放宽，
and then you can treat those two corpora as
然后你可以将这两个语料库视为
text as though they were two different languages,
文本好像是两种不同的语言，
and you can train an unsupervised machine translation model,
你可以训练一个无人监督的机器翻译模型，
uh, to convert from one to the other.
呃，从一个转换到另一个。
Uh, and you can see these examples, um,
呃，你可以看到这些例子，嗯，
the model actually does a pretty good job of sort of minimally changing the sentence,
该模型实际上可以很好地改变句子，
kind of preserving a lot of that sentence's original semantics,
保留了很多句子的原始语义，
um, such that the target attribute is changed.
嗯，这样就改变了目标属性。
Um, I also wanna throw a little bit of cold water on this idea.
嗯，我也想对这个想法投入一点冷水。
So I do think it's really exciting and- and almost kind of
所以我认为这真的很令人兴奋 - 而且差不多
mind-blowing that you can do this translation without labeled data.
令人兴奋的是你可以在没有标记数据的情况下进行翻译。
Um, certainly, right.
嗯，当然，对。
It's really hard to imagine someone giving me a bunch of books in Italian and say, "Okay.
很难想象有人用意大利语给我一堆书并说：“好的。
We're in Italian," um, without, you know,
我们是意大利人，“嗯，没有，你知道，
teaching you how to specifically do the translation.
教你如何专门做翻译。
Um, but, um, even though these methods show promise,
嗯，但是，嗯，即使这些方法显示出希望，
um, mostly they have shown promise on languages that are quite closely related.
嗯，大多数人都对与语言密切相关的语言表现出了希望。
So those previous results,
那些以前的结果，
those were all, um,
那些都是，嗯，
some combination of English to French or English to German,
英语到法语或英语到德语的某种组合，
um, or so on, and those languages are quite similar.
嗯，等等，那些语言非常相似。
[NOISE] Um, so if you look at, uh,
[NOISE]嗯，如果你看，呃，
a different language pair, let's say English to Turkish,
一个不同的语言对，让我们说英语到土耳其语，
where, um, the linguistics in those two languages are quite different, uh,
在哪里，嗯，这两种语言的语言学是完全不同的，呃，
these methods do still work to some extent, um,
这些方法在某种程度上仍然有效，嗯，
so they get around five BLEU points let's say, uh,
所以他们得到了五个BLEU点，让我们说，呃，
but they don't work nearly as well,
但他们几乎没有工作，
um, as they do in the f- uh, i- in the other settings, right?
嗯，正如他们在f-uh中所做的那样，在其他环境中，对吧？
So there's still a huge gap to purely supervised learning. Um, right?
因此纯粹监督学习仍然存在巨大差距。嗯，对吗？
So we're probably not, you know,
所以我们可能不是，你知道，
quite at this stage where an alien could come down and it's sort of, no problem,
在这个阶段，一个外星人可以下来，这是一种，没有问题，
let's use our unsupervised machine translation system, um,
让我们使用我们的无监督机器翻译系统，嗯，
but I still think that's pretty exciting progress. Um, yeah. Question?
但我仍然认为这是非常令人兴奋的进步。嗯，是的题？
Um, so what you're saying is that the genealogy of
嗯，所以你所说的是家谱
a language might need it to superimpose worse, right?
一种语言可能需要它叠加更糟，对吧？
Because my original thought was that if you took, for example,
因为我原来的想法是，如果你采取，例如，
like Latin, which doesn't have a word for, you know,
像拉丁语，它没有一句话，你知道，
the modern classification of car, I thought that would do more poorly. But if- but, uh, basically,
现代汽车的分类，我认为会做得更差。但是，如果 - 但是，呃，基本上，
what I'm asking is, do you think the English maps better to Latin
我问的是，你认为英语更好地映射到拉丁语
because they're both related, and worse to Turkish or is it the other way around?
因为它们都是相关的，对土耳其人来说更糟糕，还是相反？
Um, I would expect English to map quite a lot better to Latin.
嗯，我希望英语能更好地映射到拉丁语。
And I think part of the issue here is that, um,
我认为这里的部分问题是，嗯，
the difficulty in translation I think is not really at the word level.
翻译的困难我认为并不是真正的单词级别。
So I mean that certainly is an issue that words exist
所以我的意思是肯定存在一个词存在的问题
in one language that don't exist in another,
用一种在另一种语言中不存在的语言，
um, but I think actually,
嗯，但我想其实，
more substantial differences between language is at the level of like syntax,
语言之间更大的差异在于语法水平，
um, um, or you know, semantics, right?
嗯，嗯，或者你知道，语义，对吧？
How ideas are expressed.
如何表达想法。
Um, so- so I think I- I would expect Ital- Latin to have, you know,
嗯，所以我想我 - 我希望Ital-拉丁语，你知道，
relatively similar syntax to English,
语法与英语相似，
um, compared to say Turkish,
嗯，与土耳其语相比，
I imagine that is probably the bigger obstacle
我想这可能是更大的障碍
for unsupervised machine translation models.
适用于无人监督的机器翻译模型。
Um, I'm going to really quickly go into
嗯，我会很快进入
this last recent research paper which is basically taking BERT  which,
这篇最近的研究论文基本上是以BERT为主，
which you've learned about, um, correct?
你了解到的，嗯，对吗？
Yes. Okay. And making it cross-lingual.
是。好的。并使其跨语言。
Um, so, um, here's what regular BERT is, right?
嗯，所以，嗯，这是常规BERT，对吧？
We have a sequence of sentences in English.
我们有一系列英语句子。
We're going to mask out some of the words.
我们要掩盖一些话。
And we're going to ask BERT which is our transformer model, um,
我们要问BERT哪个是我们的变压器型号，嗯，
to essentially fill in the blanks and predict what were the words that were dropped out.
从根本上填补空白并预测被删除的单词是什么。
Um, what actually has already been done by Google is training a multilingual BERT .
嗯，Google实际上已经完成的是培训多语言BERT。
So what they did essentially is concatenate, um,
所以他们所做的基本上是连接，嗯，
a whole bunch of corpora in different languages and then train one model um,
一大堆不同语言的语料库，然后训练一个模型，
doing using this masked LM objective um,
使用这个蒙面的LM物镜嗯，
on all of that text at once.
立刻就所有这些文字。
And that's a publicly released model.
这是一个公开发布的模型。
Um, the, the new kind of extension to this that has recently been uh,
嗯，最近这种新的延伸，呃，
proposed by Facebook is to actually combine
Facebook提出的实际结合
this masked LM training objective um, with uh, translation.
这个蒙面的LM训练目标嗯，呃，翻译。
So what they do is sometimes give this model a in this case,
所以他们所做的有时在这种情况下给这个模型一个，
a sequence in English and a sequence in uh, French.
一个英文的序列和一个呃，法语的序列。
Um, drop out some of the words and just as before,
嗯，辍学一些话，就像以前一样，
ask the model to fill it in.
让模型填写。
And the motivation here is that, um,
这里的动机是，嗯，
this will much better cause the model
这将更好地导致模型
to understand the relation between these two languages.
了解这两种语言之间的关系。
Because if you're trying to find a fill in a English word that's been dropped,
因为如果你试图找到一个被删除的英文单词，
uh, the best way to do it if you have a translation is look
呃，如果你有翻译，最好的方法就是看
at the French side and try to find that word.
在法国方面，并尝试找到这个词。
Hopefully, that one hasn't been dropped as well.
希望那个也没有掉线。
And then you can um, much more easily fill in the blank.
然后你可以，更容易填补空白。
And uh, this actually leads to very uh,
呃，这实际上导致了呃，
substantial improvements in unsupervised machine translation.
无监督机器翻译的重大改进。
So just like BERT is used for other tasks in NLP,
就像BERT用于NLP中的其他任务一样，
they basically take this cross-lingual BERT.
他们基本上采用这种跨语言的BERT。
They use it as initialization for
他们用它作为初始化
a unsupervised machine translation system and they get, you know,
一个无人监督的机器翻译系统，你知道，
really large gains on the order of 10 BLEU points um,
在10个BLEU点的顺序上获得了很大的收益，
such that the gap between
这样的差距
unsupervised machine translation and the current supervised state of the art,
无人监督的机器翻译和当前监督的现有技术，
um, is much smaller.
嗯，要小得多。
Uh, so this is a pretty recent idea but I think it also shows promise
呃，所以这是一个非常近期的想法，但我认为它也显示出了希望
in really improving the quality of translation through using unlabeled data.
通过使用未标记的数据真正提高翻译质量。
Um, although I guess yeah, I guess in this case with BERT
嗯，虽然我猜是的，我想在这种情况下用BERT
they are using labeled translation data as well.
他们也使用带标签的翻译数据。
Any, any questions about this?
对此有任何问题吗？
Okay. Um, so that is all I'm going to say about using unlabeled data for translation.
好的。嗯，这就是我要说的关于使用未标记数据进行翻译的全部内容。
The next part of this talk is about um,
这次演讲的下一部分是关于嗯，
what happens if we really scale up these unsupervised language models.
如果我们真的扩大这些无监督的语言模型会发生什么。
Um, so in particular I'm gonna talk about GPT-2 which is a new model by OpenAI.
嗯，特别是我要谈的是OpenAI的新型号GPT-2。
That's essentially a really giant language model
这本质上是一个非常庞大的语言模型
and I think it has some interesting implications.
我认为它有一些有趣的含义。
So first of all, here's just the sizes of a bunch of different NLP models and,
首先，这里只是一堆不同NLP模型的尺寸，
um, you know, maybe a couple years ago the,
嗯，你知道，也许是几年前的，
the standard sort of
标准的
LSTM medium-size model was on the order of about 10 million parameters.
LSTM中型模型大约有1000万个参数。
Where 10- where a parameter is just a single weight let's say in the neural net um,
其中10-参数只是一个重量，让我们说在神经网络中，
ELMo and uh, GPT.
ELMo和呃，GPT。
So the original OpenAI paper before they did
所以在他们做之前的原始OpenAI论文
this GPT-2 and we're about 10 times bigger than that.
这个GPT-2，我们大约是它的10倍。
Um, GPT-2 is about another order of magnitude bigger.
嗯，GPT-2大约相当于另一个数量级。
Um, one kind of interesting comparison point here is that uh,
嗯，这里有一个有趣的比较点就是呃，
GPT-2 which is 1,5 billion parameters,
GPT-2，参数为15亿，
actually has more parameters than a honey bee brain has synapses.
实际上有比蜜蜂大脑有突触更多的参数。
Um, so that sounds kind of impressive, right?
嗯，这听起来有点令人印象深刻吧？
You know honeybees are not the smartest of
你知道蜜蜂并不是最聪明的
animals but they can still fly around and find nectar or whatever.
动物，但他们仍然可以飞来飞去寻找花蜜或其他什么。
Um, but yeah. Of course, this isn't really an apples to apples comparison, right?
嗯，但是。当然，这不是一个苹果对苹果的比较，对吗？
So a synapse and a weight in a neural net are really quite different.
因此，神经网络中的突触和重量确实非常不同。
But I just think it's one kind of interesting milestone
但我认为这是一个有趣的里程碑
let's say in terms of model size um,
让我们说模型尺寸嗯，
that has been surpassed.
已被超越。
[NOISE] Um, one thing to point out here is that um,
[NOISE]嗯，有一点要指出的是嗯，
this increasing scaling of deep learning is really a general trend uh,
深度学习这种不断增加的规模确实是一种普遍的趋势呃，
in all of machine learning so beyond NLP.
所有的机器学习都超越了NLP。
So this plot is showing time on the x-axis and the y-axis is log scaled um,
所以这个图是在x轴上显示时间，y轴是对数缩放的，
the amount of petaFLOPS used to train this model.
用于训练此模型的petaFLOPS数量。
Um, so what this means is that the trend at least currently is that there is
嗯，这意味着至少目前的趋势是存在的
exponential growth in how much compute power
计算能力的指数增长
we're throwing at our machine learning models.
我们正在投入我们的机器学习模型。
I guess it is kind of unclear, you know,
我想这有点不清楚，你知道，
will exponential growth continue but certainly um,
将指数增长继续，但肯定，嗯，
there's rapid growth in the size of our models.
我们的模型尺寸快速增长。
And it's leading to some really amazing results, right?
它会导致一些非常惊人的结果，对吧？
So here are results not from language but for vision.
所以这里的结果不是语言，而是视觉。
Um, this is a generative adversarial network
嗯，这是一个生成性的对抗网络
that's been trained on a lot of data and it's been trained on really large scales.
那是经过大量数据训练的，并且已经在很大的范围内进行了训练。
So it's a big model kind of in-between the size of ELMo and BERT let's say.
因此，这是ELMo和BERT之间的大型模型。
And uh, these photos here are actually productions of the model.
呃，这些照片实际上是模型的制作。
So those aren't real photos.
所以那些不是真实的照片。
Those are things the model has just kind of hallucinated out of thin air.
这些模型只是凭空产生的幻觉。
And at least to me they look essentially photo-realistic.
至少在我看来，它们看起来基本上是照片般逼真的。
There's also a website that um, is fun to look at it.
还有一个网站，嗯，看起来很有趣。
If you're not- if you're interested which is,
如果你不是 - 如果你感兴趣的是，
thispersondoesnotexist.com.
thispersondoesnotexist.com。
So if you go there, you'll see
所以，如果你去那里，你会看到
a very convincing photo of a person but it's not a real photo.
一张非常令人信服的照片，但这不是一张真正的照片。
It's again like a hallucinated image produced by a GAN.
它再次像GAN产生的幻觉图像。
We're also seeing really huge models being used for image recognition.
我们也看到真正用于图像识别的巨大模型。
So this is recent work by Google where they trained
所以这是他们最近在Google培训的工作
an image net model with half a billion parameters.
具有5亿个参数的图像网模型。
So that's bigger than BERT but not as big as GPT-2.
所以这比BERT大，但没有GPT-2那么大。
Um, this plot here is showing a
嗯，这个情节在这里显示了一个
log scaled number of parameters on the x-axis and then accuracy at ImageNet
记录x轴上参数的缩放数量，然后是ImageNet的精度
on the y-axis- axis and sort of unsurprisingly bigger models perform better.
在y轴 - 轴和一些不出所料的大型模型表现更好。
And there seems to actually be a pretty consistent trend here which is uh,
这里似乎有一个非常一致的趋势，呃，
accuracy is increasing with the log of the, the model size.
精度随着模型尺寸的对数而增加。
Um, I wanna go into a little bit more detail, how is it
嗯，我想更详细一点，它是怎么回事
possible that we can scale up models and train models at such a large extent.
我们可以在很大程度上扩展模型和训练模型。
One answer is just better hardware.
一个答案就是更好的硬件。
And in particular, um,
特别是，嗯，
there's a growing uh,
呃正在增长，
number of companies that are developing hardware specifically for deep learning.
正在开发专门用于深度学习的硬件的公司数量。
So these are even more kind of constrained and the
所以这些更受限制了
kind of operations they can do than a GPU,
他们可以做的操作比GPU，
um but they do those operations even faster.
嗯，但他们更快地完成这些操作。
So Google's Tensor Processing Units is one example.
所以谷歌的Tensor Processing Units就是一个例子。
There are actually a bunch of other companies working on this idea.
实际上有很多其他公司在研究这个想法。
Um, the other way to scale up models is by taking advantage of
嗯，扩大模型的另一种方法是利用
parallelism and there's two kinds of parallelism that I want to talk about very briefly.
并行性，我想简单地谈谈两种并行性。
So one is data parallelism.
所以一个是数据并行性。
In this case, each of your,
在这种情况下，你的每一个，
let's say GPUs, will have a copy of the model.
让我们说GPU，将有一个模型的副本。
And what you essentially do is split
你基本上做的是拆分
the mini-batch that you're training on across these different models.
您正在这些不同型号上进行培训的小批量产品。
So if you have, let's say,
所以如果你有，让我们说，
16 GPUs and each of them see a batch size of 32.
16个GPU，每个GPU的批量大小为32。
You can aggregate the gradients of these 16 uh, uh,
你可以聚合这些16 uh的渐变，呃，
if you do a back-prop on these 16 GPUs and you end up with effectively a batch size of 512.
如果你对这16个GPU进行反向支持，最终你的批量大小为512。
So this allows you to train models much faster.
因此，这可以让您更快地训练模型。
Um, the other kind of parallelism that's growing in importance is model par- parallelism.
嗯，另一种越来越重要的并行性是模型并行性。
Um, so eventually models get so big that they
嗯，所以最终模特变得如此之大
can't even fit on a single GPU and they can't even do a batch size of one.
甚至不能适用于单个GPU，它们甚至不能做一个批量大小。
Um, in this case,
嗯，在这种情况下，
you actually need to split up the model across
你实际上需要将模型分开
multiple computers- multiple compute units.
多台计算机 - 多个计算单元。
Um, and that's what's done for models kind of the size of,
嗯，这就是那种大小的模型所做的，
of let's say GPT-2.
让我们说GPT-2。
There are new frameworks such as Mesh-TensorFlow, um,
有一些新的框架，比如Mesh-TensorFlow，嗯，
which are basically designed to make this sort of model parallelism easier.
它们基本上是为了使这种模型并行化更容易。
Um, okay. So onto GPT-2, um,
嗯，好的。所以去GPT-2，嗯，
I know you already saw this a little bit in the contextualized uh,
我知道你已经在语境中看到了这一点呃，
um, embeddings um, lecture but I'm going to go into some more depth here.
嗯，嵌入式，讲课，但我会在这里深入探讨。
[NOISE] So so essentially it's a really large transformer language model.
[NOISE]所以基本上它是一个非常大的变换器语言模型。
Um, so there's nothing really kind of novel here in terms
嗯，所以这里没有什么真正的小说
of new training algorithms or in terms of um,
新的训练算法或um，
the loss function or anything like that.
损失函数或类似的东西。
Um, the thing that makes it different from
嗯，让它与众不同的东西
prior work is that it's just really really big.
以前的工作是它真的很大。
Uh, it's trained on a correspondingly huge amount of text.
呃，它训练了相应的大量文本。
So it's trained on 40 gigabytes and that's roughly 10 times larger than previous uh,
所以它训练了40千兆字节，大约是以前的10倍，
language models have been trained on.
语言模型已经过培训。
Um, when you have that size of dataset,
嗯，当你有那么大的数据集时，
um, the only way to get that much text is essentially to go to the web.
嗯，获得那么多文本的唯一方法就是去网上。
Um, so one thing OpenAI put a quite a bit of effort into when they're developing
嗯，所以OpenAI在开发过程中付出了相当大的努力
this network was to ensure that that text was pretty high-quality.
这个网络是为了确保该文本非常高质量。
Um, and they did that in a kind of interesting way.
嗯，他们以一种有趣的方式做到了。
They, they looked at Reddit which is this website where people uh,
他们，他们看着Reddit，这是人们呃这个网站，
can vote on links.
可以投票链接。
And then they said uh, if
然后他们说呃，如果
a link has a lot of votes then it's probably sort of a decent link.
一个链接有很多投票，那么它可能是一个不错的链接。
There's probably um, you know,
可能嗯，你知道，
reasonable text there for a model to learn.
合理的文字有一个模型可供学习。
Um, okay, so if we have
嗯，好的，如果有的话
this super huge language model like
这个超级庞大的语言模型就像
GPT-2 on this question of what can you actually do with it,
GPT-2关于你可以用它做什么的这个问题，
um, well obviously if you have a language model you can do language modelling with it.
嗯，很明显，如果你有一个语言模型，你可以用它进行语言建模。
Uh, but one thing kind of interestingly interesting is that you
呃，但有一点有趣的是你
can run this language model on er,
可以在er上运行这个语言模型，
existing benchmarks, um, for,
现有基准，嗯，for，
for language modelling, um,
对于语言建模，嗯，
and it gets state of the art perplexity on these benchmarks even
它甚至可以在这些基准测试中获得最先进的困惑
though it never sees the training data for these benchmarks, right?
虽然从未见过这些基准的训练数据，对吧？
So normally, if you want to say evaluate your language model on the Penn Treebank.
通常情况下，如果你想在Penn Treebank上评估你的语言模型。
You first train on the Penn Treebank and then you evaluate on this held-out set.
你首先在Penn Treebank上训练，然后你对这个保持套装进行评估。
Uh, in this case, uh,
呃，在这种情况下，呃，
a GPT-2 just by virtue of having seen so much text and being such a large model,
GPT-2只是因为看过这么多文字而成为如此庞大的模特，
outperforms all these other uh,
优于其他所有呃，
prior works even though it's not seeing that data.
以前的工作，即使它没有看到这些数据。
Um, on a bunch of different uh, language modelling benchmarks.
嗯，在一堆不同的呃，语言建模基准。
Um, but there's a bunch of other interesting experiments that OpenAI
嗯，但OpenAI还有其他一些有趣的实验
ran with this language modeling and these were based on zero-shot learning.
使用这种语言建模，这些是基于零射击学习。
So zero-shot learning just means trying to do a task without ever training on it.
所以零射击学习只是意味着在没有接受过训练的情况下尝试完成任务。
And, uh, the way you can do this with a language model
而且，呃，你可以用语言模型做到这一点
is by designing a prompt you feed into
是通过设计你提供的提示
the language model and then have it just generate from there and
语言模型，然后让它从那里生成
hopefully it generates something relevant to the task you're trying to solve.
希望它能产生与你想要解决的任务相关的东西。
So for example, for reading comprehension,
例如，对于阅读理解，
what you can do is take the context paragraph,
你可以做的是采取上下文段落，
uh, concatenate the question to it and then add uh,
呃，将问题连接到它然后添加呃，
a colon which is a way,
一个结肠，这是一种方式，
I guess, of telling the model,
我想，告诉模特，
''Okay you should be producing an answer to this question,''
“好的，你应该回答这个问题，”
and then just have it generate text, um,
然后让它生成文本，嗯，
and perhaps it'll generate something that is actually answering,
也许它会产生实际回答的东西，
um, the question and is,
嗯，问题是，
is paying attention to the context.
正在关注背景。
[NOISE] Um, and similarly, for summarization,
[NOISE]嗯，同样，对于摘要，
you can get the article then TL;DR and perhaps the model will produce the summary.
你可以得到文章然后TL; DR和模型可能会产生摘要。
Um, you can even do translation,
嗯，你甚至可以做翻译，
where you give the model,
在哪里给出模型，
um, some ex- a list of known English to French translations so you, sort of,
嗯，一些已知的英语到法语翻译列表，所以你，有点像，
prime it to tell it that it should be doing translation and then you give
我要告诉它它应该做翻译，然后你给
it the source sequence equals blank and have it just run and,
它的源序列等于空白并让它刚刚运行，
um, perhaps it'll generate,
嗯，也许它会产生，
um, the sequence in the target language.
嗯，目标语言中的序列。
Um, okay. So so here's what the results look like.
嗯，好的。所以这就是结果的样子。
Um, for all of these,
嗯，对于所有这些，
uh, the X-axis is,
呃，X轴是，
is log scaled model size and the Y-axis is accuracy, um,
是按比例缩放的模型大小，Y轴是精度，嗯，
and the dotted lines basically correspond to,
和虚线基本对应，
um, existing works on these tasks.
嗯，现有的工作就是完成这些任务。
Um, so for most of these tasks, um,
嗯，对于大多数这些任务，嗯，
GPT-2 is quite a bit below existing systems,
GPT-2比现有系统低很多，
um, but there's of course this big difference, right?
嗯，但当然这有很大的不同，对吧？
Existing systems are trained specifically to do,
现有系统经过专门培训，
um, whatever task they're being evaluated on,
嗯，无论他们正在评估什么任务，
where GPT-2 is um,
GPT-2在哪里，
only trained to do language modeling and as it learns language modeling,
只训练进行语言建模，并学习语言建模，
it's sort of picking up on these other tasks.
它有点接受这些其他任务。
Um, so right. So for example, um,
嗯，好吧。所以，例如，嗯，
it does, uh, English to French machine translation, um,
它，呃，英语到法语机器翻译，嗯，
not as well as, uh,
不是，呃，
standard unsupervised machine translation which is those, uh,
标准无监督机器翻译，那些，呃，
dotted lines, um, but it still,
虚线，嗯，但它仍然，
it still does quite well.
它仍然很好。
And, um, one thing, kind of,
而且，嗯，有一点，有点，
interesting is the trend line, right,
有趣的是趋势线，对，
for almost all of these tasks.
几乎所有这些任务。
Um, performance is getting uh,
嗯，表现越来越呃，
much better as the model increases in size.
随着模型尺寸的增加，情况要好得多。
[NOISE] Um, I think a particularly interesting,
[NOISE]嗯，我觉得特别有趣，
uh, one of these tasks is machine translation, right?
呃，这些任务之一是机器翻译，对吧？
So the question is, how can it be doing
所以问题是，它是如何做的
machine translation when all we're giving it as a bunch of
机器翻译，当我们把它作为一堆
web pages and those web pages are almost all in
网页和那些网页几乎都在
English and yet somehow it sort of magically picks up uh,
英语，但不知怎的，它有点神奇地捡起来，
a little bit of machine translation, right.
一点机器翻译，对吧。
So it's not a great model but it can still,
所以它不是一个伟大的模型，但它仍然可以，
um, you know, do a decent job in some cases.
嗯，你知道，在某些情况下做得不错。
Um, and the answer is that,
嗯，答案是，
if you look at this giant corpus of English,
如果你看看这个巨大的英语语料库，
occasionally, uh, within, within that corpus,
偶尔，呃，在那个语料库内，
you see examples of translations, right?
你看到翻译的例子，对吧？
So you see, um,
所以你看，嗯，
a French idiom and its translation or
法语成语及其翻译或
a quote from someone who's French and then the translation in English.
引用来自法语的人，然后是英文翻译。
And, um, kind of,
而且，嗯，有点，
amazingly I think this big model, um,
令人惊讶的是我觉得这个大模型，嗯，
sees enough of these examples that it actually starts to learn how to generate French,
看到足够的这些例子，它实际上开始学习如何生成法语，
um, even though that wasn't really,
嗯，即使那不是真的，
sort of, an intended part of its training.
一种，是其培训的预期部分。
Um, another interesting, um,
嗯，另一个有趣的，嗯，
thing to dig a bit more into is its ability to do question answering.
更深入挖掘的是它能够回答问题的能力。
So uh, a simple baseline for question answering gets about 1% accuracy,
那么，一个简单的问答基线可以获得大约1％的准确率，
GPT-2 barely does better at 4% accuracy.
GPT-2在4％的准确率下几乎没有做得更好。
So this isn't, like, you know,
所以这不是，就像你知道的那样
super amazingly solved question answering, um, but, um,
超级惊人地解决了问题，嗯，但是，嗯，
it's still pretty interesting in that,
它仍然非常有趣，
if you look at answers the model's most confident about,
如果你看看模特最有信心的答案，
you can see that it sort of
你可以看到它
has learned some facts about the world, right.
正确地了解了有关这个世界的一些事实。
So it's learned that Charles Darwin wrote Origin of Species.
据了解，查尔斯达尔文撰写了物种起源。
Um, normally in the history of NLP, if you want to get, kind of,
嗯，通常在NLP的历史中，如果你想得到的，那种，
world knowledge into an NLP system,
世界知识进入NLP系统，
you'd need something like a big database of facts.
你需要像大事实数据库这样的东西。
And even though this is still,
即使这仍然是，
kind of, very early stages and that, um,
那种非常早期的阶段，嗯，
there's still a huge gap between 4% accuracy and the, uh, you know,
4％的准确度和呃之间仍然存在巨大的差距，呃，你知道，
70% or so that, uh,
70％左右，呃，
state of the art open domain question answering systems can do,
最先进的开放域名问答系统可以做到，
um, it, it, um,
嗯，它，它，嗯，
it still can, uh,
它仍然可以，呃，
pick up some world knowledge just by reading a lot of text, um, without,
通过阅读大量文本来获取一些世界知识，嗯，没有，
kind of, explicitly having that knowledge put into the model.
有点明确地将这些知识放入模型中。
Um, any questions by the way on GPT-2 so far?
嗯，到目前为止，GPT-2上有任何问题吗？
Okay. So one question that's interesting to think about is,
好的。所以有一个值得思考的问题是，
what happens if our models get even bigger?
如果我们的模型变得更大，会发生什么？
Um, so here I've done the, um,
嗯，所以我在这里完成了，嗯，
very scientific thing of drawing some lines in PowerPoint and seeing where they meet up.
非常科学的东西，在PowerPoint中绘制一些线条，看看他们在哪里见面。
Um, and you can see that, um,
嗯，你可以看到，嗯，
if the trend holds at about 1 trillion parameters,
如果趋势持续约1万亿参数，
um, we get to human level reading comprehension performance.
嗯，我们达到了人类水平的阅读理解能力。
Um, so if that's true it would be really astonishing.
嗯，如果这是真的，那真是令人惊讶。
I actually do expect that a 1 trillion parameter model would be attainable in,
我实际上确实可以获得1万亿参数模型，
I don't know, ten years or so,
我不知道，十年左右，
um, but of course,
嗯，当然，
right, the trend isn't clear.
对，趋势不明确。
So if you look at summarization for example,
所以，如果你看一下摘要，例如，
it seems like performance is already,
表现似乎已经，
uh, uh, topped out.
呃，呃，超过了。
Um, so I think this will be a really interesting thing kinda going forward,
嗯，所以我觉得这将是一件非常有趣的事情，
looking at the future of NLP, um,
看着NLP的未来，嗯，
is how the scaling will change,
缩放是如何改变的，
um, the way NLP is approached.
嗯，接近NLP的方式。
Um, the other interesting thing about GPT-2 was its reaction from uh,
嗯，关于GPT-2的另一个有趣的事情是它的反应来自呃，
the media and also from other researchers.
媒体和其他研究人员。
Um, and the real cause of
嗯，真正的原因
a lot of the controversy about it was this statement from OpenAI.
很多关于它的争议都来自OpenAI的这一声明。
They said that, ''We're not going to release our full language model,
他们说，''我们不会发布我们的全语言模型，
um, because it's too dangerous,
嗯，因为它太危险了，
you know, our language model is too good.''
你知道，我们的语言模型太好了。''
Um, so the media really enjoyed this and,
嗯，所以媒体真的很喜欢这个，
you know, said that,
你知道，说，
uh, machine learning is going to break the Internet.
呃，机器学习将打破互联网。
Um, there's also some pretty interesting reactions from our researchers, right.
嗯，我们的研究人员也有一些非常有趣的反应，对吧。
So um, there's some,
嗯，有一些，
kind of, tongue-in-cheek responses here, right.
对，这里有一种诙谐的回答，对吧。
You know, I trained the model on MNIST.
你知道，我在MNIST上训练了这个模型。
Is it too dangerous for me to release it?
释放它对我来说太危险了吗？
Um, and similarly, we've done really great work
嗯，同样地，我们做了很棒的工作
but we can't release it it's too dangerous so you're just gonna have to trust us on this.
但我们不能释放它太危险了，所以你只需要相信我们。
Looking at more, kind of, reasoned, um,
看着更多，有点，有理由，嗯，
debate about this issue,
关于这个问题的辩论，
you still see articles,
你还看文章，
um, arguing both sides.
嗯，争论双方。
So these are two ar- articles,
所以这些是两篇文章，
um, from The Gradient which is a, sort of,
嗯，来自The Gradient是一种，有点像，
machine learning newsletter, um,
机器学习通讯，嗯，
and they're arguing precisely opposite sides of this issue,
他们正在争论这个问题正好相反的一面，
um, should it be released or not.
嗯，是否应该被释放。
So I guess I can briefly go over a few arguments for or against.
所以我想我可以简单地讨论一些赞成或反对的论点。
There is, kind of, a lot of debate about this and I don't want to
关于这个，有很多争论，我不想
go too deep into a controversial issue,
深入探讨一个有争议的问题，
um, but here's a long list of,
嗯，但这里有一长串清单，
kind of, things people have said about this, right.
有点，人们对此有所说的，对吧。
So um, here's why you should release.
嗯，这就是你应该发布的原因。
One complaint is that,
一个抱怨是，
is this model really that special?
这个型号真的那么特别吗？
There's nothing new going on here.
这里没什么新鲜事。
It's just 10 times bigger than previous models, um,
它比以前的型号大10倍，嗯，
and there's also some arguments that,
并且还有一些论点，
um, even if this one isn't released, you know,
嗯，即使这个没有发布，你知道，
in five years everybody can train a model this good, um,
在五年内，每个人都可以训练一个好的模型，嗯，
and actually if you look at image recognition or look at images and speech data, um,
实际上，如果你看图像识别或看图像和语音数据，嗯，
it already is possible to synthesize highly convincing,
它已经有可能合成非常有说服力，
um, fake images and fake speech.
嗯，假图像和假言论。
So kinda, what makes this thing different from those other, um, systems.
有点，是什么让这个东西与其他系统不同。
And speaking of other systems, right,
说到其他系统，对，
Photoshop has existed for a long time,
Photoshop已存在很长时间了，
so we can already convincingly fake images, um,
所以我们已经可以令人信服地伪造图像了，嗯，
people have just learned to adjust and learned
人们刚学会调整和学习
that you shouldn't always trust what's in an image,
你不应该总是相信图像中的内容，
um, because it may have been,
嗯，因为它可能是，
um, altered in some way.
嗯，以某种方式改变了。
Um, on the other hand, you could say,
嗯，另一方面，你可以说，
''Okay, uh, Photoshop exists but, um, you can't, sort of,
“好吧，呃，Photoshop存在，但是，你不能，有点像，
scale up Photoshop and start mass producing fake content the way you can with this sort
扩大Photoshop并以这种方式开始批量生产虚假内容
of model,'' and they pointed at the danger of uh, fake news, um,
模特，''他们指着呃，假新闻的危险，嗯，
fake reviews, um, in general just astroturfing, which means basically,
假的评论，嗯，一般只是天体冲浪，这基本上意味着，
uh, creating fake user content that's supporting a view you want other people to hold.
呃，创建假的用户内容，支持你希望其他人持有的视图。
Um, this is actually something that's already done,
嗯，这实际上是已经完成的事情，
um, pretty widely by country- companies and governments.
嗯，相当广泛的国家 - 公司和政府。
There's a lot of evidence for this, um,
这有很多证据，嗯，
but they are of course hiring people to
但他们当然正在招人
write all these comments on news articles let's say
把所有这些评论都写在新闻文章上
and we don't want to make their job any easier
我们不想让他们的工作变得更容易
by producing a machine that could potentially do this.
通过生产可能做到这一点的机器。
So um, I'm not really gonna take a side here,
所以，嗯，我真的不想站在这里，
um, there's still a lot of debate about this.
嗯，关于这一点还有很多争论。
I think, you know,
我想，你知道，
the main, the main takeaway here is that,
主要的，这里的主要内容是，
as a community on people in machine learning and NLP,
作为机器学习和NLP人员的社区，
don't really have a handle on this, right?
对此没有真正的把握，对吧？
We are sort of caught by surprise by, um,
我们有点惊讶，嗯，
OpenAI's, um, decision here and, um, uh,
OpenAI，嗯，这里的决定，嗯，呃，
that means that, you know,
这意味着，你知道，
there really is some figuring out that needs to be done on what
确实有一些想法需要在什么上做
exactly is responsible to release publicly.
确切地负责公开发布。
What kind of research problems should we be working on and so on.
我们应该研究什么样的研究问题等等。
[NOISE] So yeah.
[NOISE]所以是的。
Any questions about uh, this,
有任何关于呃的问题，这个，
this reaction or this debate in general?
这个反应还是一般的辩论？
[NOISE] Okay.
[NOISE]好的。
Um, I think something arising from this debate is, um,
嗯，我认为这场辩论产生的一些事情是，嗯，
the question of, um,
这个问题，嗯，
should really the ML people be the people making these, sort of,
应该真的是ML人是制造这些的人，有点像，
decisions or is there a need for more interdisciplinary science where we look at, um,
决定还是需要更多的跨学科科学，我们看一下，嗯，
experts in say, computer security,
专家说，计算机安全，
um, people from social sciences,
嗯，社会科学的人，
um, you know, people who are experts in ethics,
嗯，你知道，是道德专家，
um, to look at these decisions.
嗯，看看这些决定。
Um, right. So GPT-2 was definitely one example of where suddenly it seems like,
嗯，对。所以GPT-2绝对是突然之间的一个例子，
um, our NLP technology has a lot of pitfalls, right.
嗯，我们的NLP技术有很多陷阱，对吧。
Where they could be used in a malicious way or they could cause damage.
它们可能以恶意方式使用，或者可能造成损害。
And I think this trend is only going to increase, um,
我认为这种趋势只会增加，嗯，
if you look at, kind of,
如果你看，有点，
areas of NLP that people are working on, uh,
人们正在研究的NLP领域，呃，
increasingly people are working on really high stakes applications of NLP,
越来越多的人正在研究NLP真正高风险的应用，
um, and those often have really big, um,
嗯，那些经常真的很大，嗯，
ramifications, especially if you think from the angle of bias and fairness.
影响，特别是如果你从偏见和公平的角度思考。
Um, so, so let's go over a couple examples of this, um-
嗯，所以，让我们来看几个这样的例子，嗯 -
Um, one- so some, some areas where,
嗯，有的，有些地方，
where this is happening is people are looking at,
发生这种情况的人正在看，
uh, NLP to look at judicial decisions.
呃，NLP来看待司法判决。
So for example, should this person,
所以，例如，这个人应该
uh, get bail or not?
呃，保释还是不保释？
Um, for hiring decisions, right?
嗯，招聘决定，对吧？
So you look at someone's resume,
所以你看一下某人的简历，
you run NLP on it,
你运行NLP，
and then you'd make a decision automatically,
然后你会自动做出决定，
um, sh- should we throw out this resume or not?
嗯，我们应该抛弃这份简历吗？
So do some, sort of, screening, um, grading tests.
那么做一些，筛选，嗯，评分测试。
Um, if you take the GRE, um,
嗯，如果你参加GRE，嗯，
your, your tests will be graded by a machine.
你的，你的测试将由机器评分。
Um, a person will also look at it, um,
嗯，一个人也会看着它，嗯，
but nevertheless, um, that's, you know,
但不管怎样，嗯，你知道，
a sometimes very impactful part of your life, um, when it's,
你生活中有时非常有影响力的一部分，嗯，当它的时候，
when it's the tests that, um, inf- you know,
当它是测试时，嗯，你知道吗，
affects your, um, acceptance into a school, let's say.
让我们说，影响你，嗯，接受进入学校。
Um, so I think there is- are some,
嗯，所以我觉得有一些，
some good sides of using Machine Learning in these kinds of contexts.
在这些情境中使用机器学习的一些好方面。
So one is that we can pretty quickly evaluate,
所以一个是我们可以很快评估，
a machine learning system and search out.
机器学习系统并搜索出来。
Does it have some, kind of, bias,
它是否有某种偏见，
just by running it on a bunch of data and seeing what it does,
只需在一堆数据上运行它并查看它的作用，
and also perhaps even more importantly,
也许更重要的是，
um, we can fix this, kind of,
嗯，我们可以解决这个问题，
problem if it arises, right?
如果出现问题，对吧？
So, um, it's probably easier to fix a machine learning system that screens resumes,
所以，嗯，修复一个筛选简历的机器学习系统可能更容易，
than it is to s- to fix having, you know,
你要知道的是，要解决问题，
5,000 executives that are slightly sexist or something, right?
5000名略有性别歧视的高管，对吧？
So, so in this way,
那么，就这样，
um, there is a, sort of,
嗯，还有一种，
positive angle on using machine learning in these high-stakes, um, uh, decisions.
在这些高风险，嗯，呃，决策中使用机器学习的积极角度。
Um, on the other hand, um,
嗯，另一方面，嗯，
it's been pretty well, uh, s- known,
它很好，呃，知道，
and I know you had a lecture on bias and fairness,
我知道你有关于偏见和公平的讲座，
that machine learning often reflects bias in a data-set,
机器学习经常反映数据集的偏差，
um, it can even amplify bias in the data-set.
嗯，它甚至可以放大数据集中的偏差。
Um, and there's concern of, kind of,
嗯，还有那种担心，
a feedback loop where a biased algorithm
反馈循环，其中有偏差的算法
actually will lead to the creation of more biased data,
实际上会导致创建更多有偏见的数据，
um, in which case these problems will only compound and get worse.
嗯，在这种情况下，这些问题只会复合并变得更糟。
Um, so for all of the, uh, high-impact decisions,
嗯，对于所有呃，影响很大的决定，
um, I, I had listed on that slide,
嗯，我，我已在那张幻灯片上列出，
there are examples where things have gone awry, right?
有些事情出了问题，对吧？
So Amazon had some AI that was,
所以亚马逊有一些AI，
um, working as a recruiting tool and it turned out to be sexist.
嗯，作为招聘工具工作，结果证明是性别歧视。
Um, um, there have been some, kind of,
嗯，嗯，有一些，有点，
early pilots of using AI, um,
使用人工智能的早期飞行员，嗯，
in the justice system and those also have had,
在司法系统和那些也有，
um, in some cases, really bad results.
嗯，在某些情况下，结果非常糟糕。
Um, if you look at automatic,
嗯，如果你看看自动，
automatic essay grading, um,
自动论文评分，嗯，
it's not really a great,
它真的不是很棒，
you know, NLP system, right?
你知道吗，NLP系统吧？
So here's an example, um,
所以这是一个例子，嗯，
excerpt of an essay that, um,
一篇文章的摘录，嗯，
a automatic grading system used by the GRE test gives, uh,
GRE考试使用的自动评分系统，呃，
a very high score, um,
非常高的分数，嗯，
but really it's just, kind of, a solid of,
但实际上它只是，有点，坚实，
uh, big fancy words and that's
呃，很棒的花哨的话，那就是
enough to convince the model that this is a, a great essay.
足以让模特相信这是一篇伟大的文章。
Um, the last, um,
嗯，最后一个，嗯，
area I wanna talk about where, where, um,
我想谈谈哪里，哪里，嗯，
you can see there's really some risks and
你可以看到真的存在一些风险
some pitfalls with using NLP technology, is chatbots.
使用NLP技术的一些缺陷是聊天机器人。
Um, so I think chatbots do have a side where they can be very beneficial.
嗯，所以我认为聊天机器人确实有一个可以非常有益的方面。
Um, Woebot is one example,
嗯，Woebot就是一个例子，
is this company that has this chatbot you can talk to if you're not,
这个公司有这个聊天机器人你可以谈谈，如果你不是，
um, feeling too great and it'll try to,
嗯，感觉太棒了，它会尝试，
um, I don't know, cheer you up.
嗯，我不知道，为你振作起来。
Um, so, so that, you know,
嗯，所以，你知道，
could be a- a really nice piece of technology that helps people,
可能是一个非常好的技术，可以帮助人们，
um, but on the other hand, there's some big risks.
嗯，但另一方面，存在一些很大的风险。
So, so one example is Microsoft research had a chatbot trained on tweets,
所以，一个例子是微软的研究有一个聊天机器人训练的推文，
and it started quickly saying racist things and had to be pulled.
它很快开始说种族主义的东西，不得不被拉。
Um, so I think all of this highlights that, um,
嗯，所以我想所有这些都突出了，嗯，
as NLP is becoming more effective,
随着NLP越来越有效，
people are seeing opportunities to use it in, um,
人们正在看到使用它的机会，嗯，
increasingly high-stakes decisions and although,
越来越高风险的决定，尽管如此
you know, there are some nice- there's some appeal to that,
你知道，有一些不错 - 有一些吸引力，
um, there's also a lot of risk.
嗯，还有很多风险。
Um, any more questions on, uh,
嗯，还有其他问题，呃，
this sort of social impact of NLP?
NLP的这种社会影响？
Okay. Um, last part of this lecture is looking more at future research, right?
好的。嗯，这个讲座的最后一部分是关注未来的研究，对吧？
And in particular, um,
特别是，嗯，
I think a lot of the current research trends are,
我认为目前很多研究趋势是，
kind of reactions to BERT, um, right?
那种对BERT的反应，对吧？
So, so the question is what did BERT solve and- and what do we work on next?
那么，问题是BERT解决了什么 - 以及我们接下来会做些什么？
Um, so here are results on the GLUE benchmark.
嗯，所以这里是GLUE基准测试的结果。
Um, that is, uh, a compendium of,
嗯，也就是说，呃，简历，
uh, 10 natural language understanding tasks.
呃，10种自然语言理解任务。
Um, and you get an average score across those 10 tasks.
嗯，你可以在这10个任务中得到平均分。
Um, the left, uh, two- the two are,
嗯，左边，呃，两个是两个，
sorry the right- two right most models are,
对不起右边 - 最右边的两个型号是，
um, uh, s- non, uh,
嗯，呃，非 - ，呃，
are just supervised trained machine learning systems, right?
只是受过监督训练的机器学习系统，对吗？
So we have Bag-of-Vectors, um,
所以我们有Bag-of-Vectors，嗯，
we instead use our fancy neural net architecture
我们改为使用我们的花式神经网络架构
of BiLSTM + Attention and we get about five points.
BiLSTM +注意力，我们得到大约五分。
Um, but the gains from BERT,
嗯，但BERT的收益，
uh, really dwarf that difference, right?
呃，真的让这个差异相形见绌吧？
So, so BERT improves results by about, uh,
那么，BERT通过大约改善结果，呃，
17 points and we end up being actually quite close,
17点，我们最终真的非常接近，
um, to human performance on these tasks.
嗯，人类在这些任务上的表现。
Um, so one, sort of,
嗯，所以，有点，
implication of this that people are wondering about is,
这是人们想知道的含义是，
is this, kind of, the death of architecture engineering?
这就是建筑工程的死亡吗？
Um, so I'm sure all of you who have worked on the default final project, um,
嗯，所以我相信所有参与过默认最终项目的人，嗯，
have seen a whole bunch of fancy pictures showing different,
已经看到一大堆花哨的图片显示不同，
uh, architectures for solving SQuAD.
呃，解决SQuAD的架构。
Um, there are a lot of papers.
嗯，有很多论文。
They all propose some, kind of,
他们都提出了一些，有点，
uh, attention mechanism or something like that.
呃，注意机制或类似的东西。
Um, and, um, right.
嗯，嗯，对。
With BERT, it's, sort of,
有了BERT，有点像，
um, you don't need to do any of that, right?
嗯，你不需要做那些，对吧？
You just train a transformer and you give it enough data,
你只需要训练一个变压器并给它足够的数据，
and actually you're doing great on SQuAD,
实际上你在SQUAD上做得很好，
you know, maybe, um, these, uh,
你知道，也许，嗯，这些，呃，
architectural enhancements are not necessarily, um,
架构增强不一定，嗯，
the key thing that'll drive progress in,
是推动进步的关键因素，
uh, improving results on these tasks.
呃，改善这些任务的结果。
Um, right. So, uh,
嗯，对。所以，呃，
if you look at this with the perspective of a researcher,
如果从研究人员的角度来看这个，
you can think a researcher will say, "Okay,
你可以认为研究人员会说：“好的，
I can spend six months designing a fancy new architecture for
我可以花六个月的时间设计一个奇特的新架构
SQuAD and if I do a good job maybe I'll improve results by 1, uh, F1 point."
SQuAD，如果我做得好，也许我会把结果改进1，呃，F1点。“
Um, but in the case of BERT, um,
嗯，但在BERT的情况下，嗯，
increasing the size of their model of 3x,
增加他们的3x模型的大小，
which is the difference between,
这是区别，
they've like a base size model and a large model,
他们喜欢基本尺寸模型和大型模型，
um, that improve results by 5 F1 points.
嗯，这可以提高5个F1积分。
Um, so it does seem to suggest we need to, sort of,
嗯，所以它似乎表明我们需要，有点，
re-prioritize, um, which avenues of research we'd pursue,
重新确定优先顺序，嗯，我们追求的研究途径，
because this architecture engineering isn't providing, kind of,
因为这个架构工程没有提供，有点像，
gains for its time investment the way,
通过时间投资获得收益，
uh, leveraging unlabeled data is.
呃，利用未标记的数据。
Um, so now, if you look at the SQuAD leaderboard, um,
嗯，现在，如果你看看SQuAD排行榜，嗯，
I think at least the top 20 entrants are all BERT plus something.
我认为至少前20名参赛者都是BERT加上一些东西。
Um, one other issue, uh,
嗯，另一个问题，呃，
I think BERT has raised is that,
我认为BERT提出的是，
um, we need harder tasks, right?
嗯，我们需要更艰巨的任务，对吧？
BERT has almost solved SQuAD,
BERT几乎解决了SQuAD，
if you define it by, uh,
如果你定义它，呃，
getting close to human performance.
接近人类的表现。
Um, so there's been, um,
嗯，所以有，嗯，
a growth in new datasets that are, uh,
新数据集的增长，呃，
more challenging and there are a couple of ways in which,
更具挑战性，有几种方法，
um, they can be more challenging.
嗯，他们可能更具挑战性。
So one is, um,
那么一个是，嗯，
doing reading comprehension on longer documents,
对较长的文件进行阅读理解，
or doing it across more than one document.
或者在多个文档中进行。
Um, one area is looking at c- uh,
嗯，有一个区域在看c-uh，
coming up with harder questions that require a multi-hop reasoning.
提出需要多跳推理的难题。
Um, so that essentially meas- means you have to string
嗯，所以基本上测量你必须串
together multiple supporting facts from different places,
来自不同地方的多个支持事实，
um, to produce the correct answer.
嗯，要产生正确的答案。
Um, and another area,
嗯，还有另一个地方，
situating question-answering within a dialogue.
在对话中定位问答。
Um, there's also been a, kind of,
嗯，还有一种，有点像，
small detail with the construction of reading comprehension datasets,
阅读理解数据集构建的细节，
that has actually really affected,
实际上真的受到了影响，
um, the, the difficulty of the task.
嗯，这个任务的难度。
And that is whether, um,
那就是，嗯，
when you create these datasets, um,
当你创建这些数据集时，嗯，
is the person who writes questions about a passage,
是关于段落的问题的人，
can they see that passage or not?
他们能看到那段经文吗？
Um, so of course, it's much easier to come up
嗯，当然，它更容易出现
with a question that when you see the passage,
有一个问题，当你看到这段经文，
and if you come up with a question without seeing the passage,
如果你提出一个没有看到段落的问题，
you may not even have a answerable question.
你甚至可能没有一个可回答的问题。
Um, but the problem with looking at
嗯，但看着的问题
the passage is that first of all it's not realistic, right?
这段经文首先是不现实的，对吧？
So, uh, if I'm asking a question, you know,
所以，呃，如果我问一个问题，你知道，
I'm not going to have usually
我通常不会
the paragraph that answers that question sitting in front of me.
回答那个问题的段落坐在我面前。
Um, on top of that,
嗯，最重要的是，
it really encourages easy questions, right?
它真的鼓励简单的问题，对吗？
So, um, if you're a Mechanical Turker,
所以，嗯，如果你是一名机械车手，
and you're paid to write as many questions as possible,
并且你付出了尽可能多的问题，
and then you see an article that says,
然后你看到一篇文章说，
um, I don't know, you know,
嗯，我不知道，你知道，
uh, Abraham Lincoln was the 16th president of the United States,
呃，亚伯拉罕林肯是美国第16任总统，
um, what are you gonna write?
嗯，你要写什么？
As your question, you're gonna write,
作为你的问题，你要写，
who was the 16th president of the United States.
谁是美国第16任总统。
You're not gonna write something more interesting that's harder to answer.
你不会写一些更有趣的东西，更难回答。
Um, so- so this is one way in which crowdsourced datasets have changed, um,
嗯，所以这是众包数据集发生变化的一种方式，嗯，
people are now making sure questions are,
人们现在确定问题是，
sort of, independent of, of the contexts.
一种独立于上下文的东西。
Um, so I'm gonna briefly, uh,
嗯，所以我要简单地说，呃，
go over a couple of new datasets in this line.
在这一行中查看几个新的数据集。
So one is called QuAC, which stands for Question Answering in Context.
所以一个叫做QuAC，它代表Context中的Question Answering。
Um, in this dataset,
嗯，在这个数据集中，
there is a teacher and a student,
有老师和学生，
um, the teacher sees a Wikipedia article.
嗯，老师看到一篇维基百科的文章。
The student wants to learn about this Wikipedia article,
学生想要了解这篇维基百科的文章，
and the goal is to train a machine learning model that acts as the teacher.
目标是培养充当教师的机器学习模型。
Um, so you can imagine maybe in the future, this,
嗯，所以你可以想象将来，这个，
sort of, technology would be useful for,
某种技术对我们有用，
uh, um, education for, kind of,
呃，嗯，教育，有点，
having, uh, adding some automation.
有，呃，添加一些自动化。
Um, uh, one thing that makes this task difficult is that,
嗯，呃，使这个任务变得困难的一件事是，
uh, questions depend on the entire history of the conversation.
呃，问题取决于谈话的整个历史。
Um, so for example, uh,
嗯，例如，呃，
if you look, um, on the left here, uh,
如果你看，嗯，在左边这里，呃，
the example, um, dialogue,
例子，嗯，对话，
um, the third question is was he the star?
嗯，第三个问题是他是明星吗？
Um, clearly you can't answer that question unless you look back earlier in the dialogue,
嗯，显然你不能回答这个问题，除非你在对话中回顾一下，
and realize that the subject of this,
并意识到这个主题，
uh, conversation is Daffy Duck.
呃，谈话是Daffy Duck。
Um, a- and, sort of,
嗯，等等，
because this dataset is more challenging,
因为这个数据集更具挑战性，
and you can see there's a, there's a much bigger gap to human performance, right?
而且你可以看到有一个，人类表现有更大的差距，对吗？
So if you train some BERT with some extensions, you'll st- uh,
所以，如果你训练一些带有一些扩展的BERT，你就会这样做，
the results are still like 15 F1 points worse than human performance.
结果仍然比人类表现差15个F1点。
Um, um, here's one other dataset, um, called HotPotQA.
嗯，嗯，这是另外一个名为HotPotQA的数据集。
Um, it is, uh,
嗯，是的，呃，
designed instead for multi-hop reasoning.
专为多跳推理而设计。
Um, so essentially, in order to answer a question,
嗯，基本上，为了回答一个问题，
you have to look at multiple documents,
你必须看多个文件，
you have to look at different facts from those documents,
你必须从这些文件中查看不同的事实，
and perform some inference,
并进行一些推断，
um, to get what the correct answer is.
嗯，得到正确的答案。
Um, so I think, you know, this is a- a much harder task.
嗯，所以我想，你知道，这是一项艰巨的任务。
And again, um, there's a much bigger gap between human performance.
而且，嗯，人类表现之间的差距要大得多。
Um, any questions on, uh,
嗯，有什么问题，呃，
new datasets, um, harder chi- tasks for NLP?
NLP的新数据集，嗯，更难的任务？
Okay. Um, I'm gonna,
好的。嗯，我要的，
kind of, rapid fire and go through, um,
那种，快速的火，并通过，嗯，
a couple of more areas in the last minutes of this talk.
在本次演讲的最后几分钟，还有几个领域。
Um, so multitask learning I think is really growing in importance.
嗯，我认为多任务学习的重要性正在增加。
Um, of course, um,
嗯，当然，嗯，
you've had a whole lecture on this, right?
你有关于此的整个讲座，对吧？
So I'm not gonna spend too much time on it.
所以我不会花太多时间在上面。
Um, but maybe one, uh,
嗯，但也许一个，呃，
point of interest is that if you look at performance on this GLUE benchmark,
兴趣点是，如果你看一下这个GLUE基准的表现，
so this benchmark for natural language understanding,
所以这个自然语言理解的基准，
um, all the top couple results, um,
嗯，所有顶级夫妇的结果，嗯，
are- that are now actually surpassing BERT in
是 - 现在实际上超过了BERT
performance are- is taking BERT and training it in a multi-task way.
性能是 - 采用BERT并以多任务方式对其进行培训。
Um, I think another interesting, uh,
嗯，我觉得另一个有趣的，呃，
motivation for multi-task learning is that if you are training BERT, you have a really,
多任务学习的动机是，如果你正在训练BERT，你真的，
really large model and one way to make
非常大的模型和一种制作方法
more efficient use of that model is training it to do many things at once.
更有效地使用该模型正在训练它一次做很多事情。
Another area that's definitely important, um,
另一个非常重要的领域，嗯，
and I think will be important going in the future is dealing with low-resource settings.
而且我认为将来重要的是处理资源匮乏的环境。
Um, and here I'm using a really broad,
嗯，这里我用的很宽，
uh, definition of resources, right.
呃，资源的定义，对。
So that could mean compute power, um, you know,
这可能意味着计算能力，嗯，你知道，
BERT is great but it also takes huge amounts of compute to run it.
BERT很棒，但运行它也需要大量的计算。
So it's not realistic to say,
所以说，这是不现实的，
um, if you're building, let's say a mobile, uh,
嗯，如果你正在建设，那就说一个手机，呃，
an app for a mobile device that you could run a model the size of BERT.
移动设备的应用程序，您可以运行BERT大小的模型。
Um, as I already ga- went into earlier in this talk, um, you know,
嗯，正如我早些时候在这次演讲中所说的那样，嗯，你知道，
low-resource languages is an area that I think is pretty, um,
低资源语言是我觉得很漂亮的一个领域，嗯，
under-represented in NLP research right now,
目前在NLP研究中代表性不足，
because most datasets are in English, um,
因为大多数数据集都是英文的，嗯，
but I do think, right,
但我确实认为，对，
there's a really, you know,
你知道，有一个真的，
large number of people that in order to benefit from NLP technology, um,
为了从NLP技术中受益，大量的人，嗯，
we'll need to have technologies that work well in a lot of
我们需要拥有在很多方面运作良好的技术
different languages especially those without much training data.
不同语言，特别是那些没有太多训练数据
And, um, speaking of low- low amounts of training data, I think in general this is,
而且，嗯，谈到低数量的培训数据，我认为一般来说，这是
uh, a- an interesting area of research,
呃，一个有趣的研究领域，
um, within machine learning.
嗯，在机器学习中。
Actually, people are, um,
实际上，人们，嗯，
working a lot on this as well.
在这方面也做了很多工作。
Um, so a term is often, uh,
嗯，所以一个术语经常是，呃，
a term often used is few shot learning.
经常使用的术语是很少的镜头学习。
Um, and that essentially means being able to
嗯，这基本上意味着能够
train a machine learning model that only sees,
训练只看到的机器学习模型，
let's say five or ten examples.
让我们说五个或十个例子。
Um, one motivation there is, um,
嗯，有一个动机，嗯，
I think a clear distinction between how our existing machine learning systems learn,
我认为我们现有的机器学习系统如何学习，
and how humans learn is that, um,
以及人类如何学习，嗯，
humans can generalize very quickly from five or so examples.
人类可以从五个左右的例子中迅速概括。
Um, if you're training a neural net,
嗯，如果你正在训练一个神经网络，
you normally need, you know,
你通常需要，你知道，
thousands of examples or perhaps even tens of thousands,
成千上万的例子，甚至可能成千上万，
hundreds of thousands of examples to get something that works.
成千上万的例子来获得有用的东西。
Um, so I also see this being a pretty important area in the future.
嗯，所以我也看到这是未来非常重要的一个领域。
Um, the last area where I want to go in, um,
嗯，我想进去的最后一个区域，嗯，
a little bit more depth is interpreting and understanding models.
更深入的是解释和理解模型。
Um, so, so really there's two aspects of this.
嗯，所以，这真的有两个方面。
One is if I have a machine learning model and it makes a prediction,
一个是如果我有机器学习模型并进行预测，
I would like to be able to, uh,
我希望能够，呃，
know why did it make that prediction?
知道为什么会做出预测吗？
So gets some rationale, get some explanation,
得到一些理由，得到一些解释，
um, that would especially be important in an area like health care, right?
嗯，这在医疗保健等领域尤为重要，对吧？
So if you're a doctor and you're making a decision, um,
所以，如果你是一名医生并且你正在做出决定，嗯，
it's probably not good enough for your machine learning model to say,
你的机器学习模型可能不够好，
"Patient has disease X."
“患者有疾病X.”
You really want it to say,
你真的想要它说，
"Patient has disease X for these reasons."
“由于这些原因，患者患有疾病X.”
Um, because then you as a doctor can double-check,
嗯，因为那时你作为医生可以仔细检查，
and, and try to validate the, the,
并且，并尝试验证，
uh, machine's, um, thinking I guess,
呃，机器，嗯，我想，
um, to come up with that diagnosis.
嗯，想出那个诊断。
Um, the other area of interpreting
嗯，另一个解释领域
understanding models is more of a scientific question, right?
理解模型更像是一个科学问题，对吧？
Is we know things like BERT work really well,
我们知道像BERT这样的东西真的很好用，
um, we want to know why do they work well?
嗯，我们想知道他们为什么运作良好？
What -what what aspects of language do they model?
什么 - 他们建模的语言有哪些方面？
Um, what things don't they model?
嗯，他们模特的东西不是什么？
Um, and that might lead to, um,
嗯，这可能导致，嗯，
ideas of improving, um, those- those models.
改善那些模型的想法。
Um, so, um, here is a, uh,
嗯，所以，嗯，这是一个，呃，
couple slides on the main approach for evalu- answering the sort of scientific questions.
几个幻灯片的主要方法是评估这类科学问题。
What does a machine-learning model learn?
机器学习模型学到了什么？
Um, what you do is you have a model so let's say it's BERT.
嗯，你做的是你有一个模型所以让我们说它是BERT。
It takes as input a sequence of words, um,
它需要输入一系列单词，嗯，
it produces as output a sequence of vectors, um,
它产生一系列向量作为输出，嗯，
we want to ask does it know for example,
我们想问它是否知道例如，
the part of speech of words?
单词的词性？
So, so it does in its vector representations,
所以，它在矢量表示中也是如此，
does that capture something about syntax?
这会捕获一些语法吗？
Um, and a simple way of asking this question is train another classifier on top of BERT,
嗯，问一个简单的方法就是在BERT上训练另一个分类器，
uh, that's trained to do,
呃，那是训练有素的，
um, let's say part-of-speech tagging.
嗯，让我们说一下词性标注。
Um, but we only, um,
嗯，但我们只是，嗯，
backprop into that diagnostic classifier itself.
backprop进入该诊断分类器本身。
So in other words we're treating the output of BERT, um,
换句话说，我们正在处理BERT的输出，嗯，
that sequence of vectors as a fixed input,
那个矢量序列作为固定输入，
and we're sort of probing those vectors to see,
我们正在探测那些向量，
um, do they contain, um,
嗯，他们是否包含，嗯，
information about a part of speech that
关于词性的信息
this second diagnostic classifier on top can decode,
顶部的第二个诊断分类器可以解码，
um, to get the correct labels?
嗯，要获得正确的标签？
Um, so, um, it was kind of quite a few concerns here.
嗯，嗯，这里有点担心。
Um, one concern is, uh,
嗯，一个问题是，呃，
if you make your diagnostic classifier too complicated,
如果你的诊断分类器过于复杂，
it can just solve the classif- the task all on itself,
它可以解决分类 - 任务本身，
and it can basically ignore, uh,
它基本上可以忽略，呃，
whatever representations were produced by BERT.
无论BERT产生什么样的陈述。
Um, so- so the kind of standard thing right now is to use
嗯，所以现在标准的东西就是使用
a single softmax layer on top of BERT,
BERT顶部的单个softmax层，
um, to do these decisions.
嗯，做这些决定。
Um, and there's been a whole bunch of tasks proposed for
嗯，并且提出了一大堆任务
evaluating essentially the linguistic knowledge of these models.
基本上评估这些模型的语言知识。
Um, so you could do part-of-speech tagging,
嗯，所以你可以做一些词性标注，
you could do more semantic tasks like,
你可以做更多的语义任务，比如
uh, relation extraction, um,
呃，关系提取，嗯，
or- or something like co-reference.
or-或类似共同参考的东西。
Um, and this is a pretty active area of work.
嗯，这是一个非常活跃的工作领域。
Um, here is, uh, just one, uh,
嗯，这是，呃，只有一个，呃，
plot showing some of the results, um, of this approach.
情节显示了这种方法的一些结果。
So here what we're doing is we're adding
所以我们正在做的是我们正在添加
diagnostic classifiers to different layers of BERT,
诊断分类器到不同的BERT层，
and we are seeing which layers of BERT are more useful for particular tasks.
我们看到哪些BERT层对特定任务更有用。
Um, and, um, something kind of interesting comes out of this which is that, um,
嗯，而且，嗯，有些有趣的东西来自于这个，嗯，
the different layers of BERT seem to be corresponding, um,
BERT的不同层似乎是对应的，嗯，
fairly well with notions of,
相当好的概念，
uh, different layers of li- of linguistics.
呃，不同层次的语言学。
Um, so, uh, dependency parsing which is a syntactic task,
嗯，所以，呃，依赖解析这是一个句法任务，
um, it's, uh, considered sort of a, you know,
嗯，是的，呃，被认为是一种，你知道，
medium level task in understanding a sentence.
理解句子的中级任务。
Um, the medium layers of BERT, so layers kind of 6 through 8 or something,
嗯，BERT的中间层，所以层数为6到8之类，
are the ones best at dependency parsing.
是最依赖于解析的人。
Um, if you have a se- very semantic task like sentiment analysis,
嗯，如果你有像情绪分析这样的语义任务，
um, where you're trying to learn some kind of, uh,
嗯，你在哪里学习了某种东西，呃，
semantic property of the whole sentence, um,
整个句子的语义属性，嗯，
then the very last layers of BERT are the ones that seem
那么BERT的最后几层就是那些
to encode the most information about- about this, uh, phenomenon.
编码关于这个，呃，现象的最多信息。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
So this is almost it for the talk, um,
所以这几乎是为了谈话，嗯，
I just have one slide here of, uh, um,
我这里只有一张幻灯片，呃，嗯，
NLP not in kind of the academic researching context,
NLP不是学术研究的背景，
which I have already been talking a lot about but NLP in industry,
我已经谈了很多关于NLP的工业，
and really there's rapid progress there.
那里确实有快速的进步。
And I wanted to point to you two areas where I think there's
我想指出你认为存在的两个方面
especially a large interest in using NLP technology.
尤其是对使用NLP技术的浓厚兴趣。
Um, one is dialogue,
嗯，一个是对话，
um, so for things like chatbots, right?
嗯，对于像聊天机器人这样的东西，对吧？
There's the Alexa Prize where they're actually investing a lot of money in,
有Alexa奖，他们实际投入了大量资金，
um, having groups figure out how to improve chitchat dialogue.
嗯，让小组弄清楚如何改善闲聊对话。
Um, there's also I think a lot of potential for customer service, right?
嗯，还有我认为很有潜力的客户服务，对吧？
So improving basically automated systems that'll, um,
所以改进基本上自动化的系统，嗯，嗯，
you know, book you a flight,
你知道的，给你预订航班，
or help you cancel a subscription, or anything like that.
或者帮助您取消订阅或类似的任何内容。
Um, and similarly, there's a lot of potential in health care.
嗯，同样，医疗保健也有很大的潜力。
Um, one is understanding the records of someone who,
嗯，人们正在了解某人的记录，
um, is sick and to help them- to help with diagnoses.
嗯，病了，帮助他们 - 帮助诊断。
Um, I think another, um,
嗯，我想另一个，嗯，
equally important area is actually, uh,
同样重要的领域实际上是，呃，
parsing, uh, biomedical papers.
解析，呃，生物医学论文。
Um, so, um, the number of biomedical papers that are being written is really insane,
嗯，嗯，正在编写的生物医学论文的数量真是疯了，
um, it's, it's way larger than the number
嗯，它比数字大
of computer science papers that are being written.
正在编写的计算机科学论文。
[NOISE] Um, often if you're a doctor,
[NOISE]嗯，通常如果你是医生，
or if you're a researcher, um,
或者如果你是研究员，嗯，
in medicine, you might want to look up something very specific, right?
在医学上，你可能想要查找一些非常具体的东西，对吧？
You might want to know what is
你可能想知道它是什么
the effect of this particular drug on this particular gene,
这种特殊药物对这种特殊基因的影响，
or a cell with this particular gene.
或具有该特定基因的细胞。
Um, there's no good way right now of searching through, um,
嗯，现在没有好办法搜索，嗯，
hundreds of thousands of papers to find if someone has a- has, uh,
成千上万的论文，如果有人有，有，呃，
done this experiment and have results for this,
做了这个实验并得到了这个结果，
um, particular combination of things.
嗯，特别是事物的组合。
Um, so automated reading of all this biomedical literature,
嗯，所以这些生物医学文献的自动阅读，
um, could have a lot of value.
嗯，可能有很多价值。
Okay, um, to conclude, um,
好的，嗯，总结一下，嗯，
there's been rapid progress in the last five years due to deep learning, um, in NLP.
由于深入学习，嗯，在NLP，过去五年来取得了快速进展。
Um, in the last year, we've seen another really kind of, uh,
嗯，在去年，我们看到了另一种真正的，呃，
a dramatic increase in the capability of our systems,
我们系统的能力急剧增加，
thanks to, uh, using unlabeled data.
谢谢，呃，使用未标记的数据。
So that's methods like BERT.
这就像BERT这样的方法。
Um, and, um, the other kind of thing that's I think important to think about is that,
嗯，嗯，我认为重要的另一件事是，
NLP systems are starting to be at a place where they can have big social impact.
NLP系统开始处于一个可以产生巨大社会影响的地方。
Um, so that makes some issues like bias and security very important. Um, thank you.
嗯，这使得偏见和安全等问题非常重要。嗯，谢谢。
Uh, good luck finishing all your projects.
呃，祝你好运完成所有项目。
[APPLAUSE].
[掌声]。